<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">Health informatics--Point-of-care medical device communication Part 10103: Nomenclature--Implantable device, cardiac</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">Health informatics--Point-of-care medical device communication Part 10103: Nomenclature--Implantable device, cardiac</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6291727</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 11073-10103-2012</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-7282-8</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2012.6291727</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>11073-10103-2012</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2012-10-19</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2012-08-27</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2012-08-30</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2012-05-14</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">The base nomenclature provided in IEEE 11073 to support terminology for implantable cardiac devices is extended in this standard. Devices within the scope of this nomenclature are implantable devices such as pacemakers, defibrillators, devices for cardiac resynchronization therapy, and implantable cardiac monitors. The discrete terms necessary to convey a clinically relevant summary of the information obtained during a device interrogation are defined in this nomenclature. To improve workflow efficiencies, cardiology and electrophysiology practices require the management of summary interrogation information from all vendor devices and systems in a central system such as an Electronic Health Records (EHR) system or a device clinic management system. To address this requirement, the Implantable Device, Cardiac (IDC) Nomenclature defines a standard-based terminology for device data. The nomenclature facilitates the transfer of data from the vendor proprietary systems to the clinic EHR or device clinic management system.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">The base nomenclature provided in IEEE 11073 to support terminology for implantable cardiac devices is extended in this standard. Devices within the scope of this nomenclature are implantable devices such as pacemakers, defibrillators, devices for cardiac resynchronization therapy, and implantable cardiac monitors. The discrete terms necessary to convey a clinically relevant summary of the information obtained during a device interrogation are defined in this nomenclature. To improve workflow efficiencies, cardiology and electrophysiology practices require the management of summary interrogation information from all vendor devices and systems in a central system such as an Electronic Health Records (EHR) system or a device clinic management system. To address this requirement, the Implantable Device, Cardiac (IDC) Nomenclature defines a standard-based terminology for device data. The nomenclature facilitates the transfer of data from the vendor proprietary systems to the clinic EHR or device clinic management system. Additional files can be found at http://standards.ieee.org/downloads/11073/11073-10103-2012/ if not attached to the PDF.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2012</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Informatics</keyword>
  <keyword>Medical devices</keyword>
  <keyword>Bioinformatics</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomedical informatics</keyword>
  <keyword>Implantable biomedical devices</keyword>
  <keyword>Pacemakers</keyword>
  <keyword>Remote monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomedical monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT)</keyword>
  <keyword>codes</keyword>
  <keyword>follow-up</keyword>
  <keyword>home monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE 11073-10103</keyword>
  <keyword>implantable cardioverter defibrillator (ICD)</keyword>
  <keyword>implantable devices</keyword>
  <keyword>medical device communication</keyword>
  <keyword>nomenclature</keyword>
  <keyword>pacemaker</keyword>
  <keyword>remote follow-up</keyword>
  <keyword>remote monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>terminology</keyword>
</bibdata>