<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Testing and Performance for Optical Ground Wire (OPGW) for Use on Electric Utility Power Lines</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">Redline</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Testing and Performance for Optical Ground Wire (OPGW) for Use on Electric Utility Power Lines - Redline</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5981357</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 1138-2009 (Revision of IEEE Std 1138-1994) - Redline</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-6906-4</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>1138-2009</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2009-11-30</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2013-08-15</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2009-09-11</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard covers the performance, test requirements, procedures, and acceptance criteria for a transmission line overhead ground wire (a.k.a. shield wire, static wire, earth wire, skywire) with optical fibers commonly known as optical ground wire (OPGW). An OPGW cable has the dual performance functions of a ground wire with telecommunications capabilities. This standard includes functional requirements such as electrical, mechanical, optical fiber, environmental and packaging, and test requirements related to design, installation, in-service, maintenance, including routine tests. This standard is not intended to supersede any established safety rules, codes, regulations, or practices associated with the use of OPGW cables. It is the responsibility of the user of this standard to establish appropriate safety and health practices and to determine the applicability of regulatory limitations prior to use.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2011</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Optical fiber devices</keyword>
  <keyword>Wiring</keyword>
  <keyword>Ground support</keyword>
  <keyword>Power transmission lines</keyword>
  <keyword>Electricity supply industry</keyword>
  <keyword>Testing</keyword>
  <keyword>1138-2009</keyword>
  <keyword>fiber optic ground wire</keyword>
  <keyword>laboratory tests</keyword>
  <keyword>OPGW</keyword>
  <keyword>optical ground wire</keyword>
  <keyword>type tests</keyword>
</bibdata>