<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard Specification for Public Key Cryptographic Techniques Based on Hard Problems over Lattices</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard Specification for Public Key Cryptographic Techniques Based on Hard Problems over Lattices</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4800404</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 1363.1-2008</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-5863-1</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2009.4800404</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>1363.1-2008</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2009-05-05</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2009</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2020-01-15</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2008-12-10</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Specifications of common public key cryptographic techniques based on hard problems over lattices supplemental to those considered in IEEE Std 1363-2000 and IEEE Std 1363a-2004, including mathematical primitives for secret value (key) derivation, public key encryption, identification and digital signatures, and cryptographic schemes based on those primitives are provided. Also presented are specifications of related cryptographic parameters, public keys, and private keys. Class of computer and communications systems is not restricted.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Specifications of common public-key cryptographic techniques based on hard problems over lattices supplemental to those considered in IEEE 1363 and IEEE P1363a, including mathematical primitives for secret value (key) derivation, public-key encryption, identification and digital signatures, and cryptographic schemes based on those primitives. Specifications of related cryptographic parameters, public keys and private keys. Class of computer and communications systems is not restricted.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2009</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>1363.1-2008</keyword>
  <keyword>encryption</keyword>
  <keyword>lattice-based cryptography</keyword>
  <keyword>public key cryptography</keyword>
</bibdata>