<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Grounding of Industrial Power Systems</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Grounding of Industrial Power Systems</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7366528</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE No 142-1956</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-0161-6</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1960.7366528</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>142-1956</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2016-01-29</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1960</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2015-12-25</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1960-09-01</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Looking at the problem from an overall standpoint, the grounding of the system would in most cases be done by making a metallic connection direct or through an impedance between transformer or generator neutrals and the building grounding system which is described in Chapter II. The grounding system described in Chapter II in turn is connected to earth through the system of ground rods and water pipes described in Chapter IV.The protective systems discussed for static and lightning protection in Chapter III would likewise be connected to the ground rods and water pipe system as outlined in Chapter IV.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Looking at the problem from an overall standpoint, the grounding of the system would in most cases be done by making a metallic connection direct or through an impedance between transformer or generator neutrals and the building grounding system which is described in Chapter II. The grounding system described in Chapter II in turn is connected to earth through the system of ground rods and water pipes described in Chapter IV. The protective systems discussed for static and lightning protection in Chapter III would likewise be connected to the ground rods and water pipe system as outlined in Chapter IV.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1956</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Grounding</keyword>
  <keyword>Industrial power systems</keyword>
  <keyword>Lightning</keyword>
  <keyword>Conductors</keyword>
  <keyword>Resistance</keyword>
</bibdata>