<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Extensions to Standard Test Interface Language (STIL) (IEEE Std. 1450-1999) for Tester Target Specification</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Extensions to Standard Test Interface Language (STIL) (IEEE Std. 1450-1999) for Tester Target Specification</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4301375</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 1450.3-2007</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-5518-0</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2007.4301375</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>1450.3-2007</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2008-03-17</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2007</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2014-02-03</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2007-03-08</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">The STIL environment supports transferring tester-independent test programs to a specific automated testing equipment (ATE) system. Although native STIL data are tester independent, the actual process of mapping the test program onto tester resources may be critical, and it is necessary to be able to completely and unambiguously specify how the STIL programs and patterns are mapped onto the tester resources. TRC (which stands for either tester resource constraints or tester rules checking, depending on the usage) is an extension to the STIL language to facilitate this operation.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">The STIL environment supports transferring tester-independent test programs to a specific ATE system. Although native STIL data are tester independent, the actual process of mapping the test program onto tester resources may be critical, and it is necessary to be able to completely and unambiguously specify how the STIL programs and patterns are mapped onto the tester resources. TRC (which stands for either tester resource constraints or tester rules checking, depending on the usage) is an extension to the STIL language to facilitate this operation.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2007</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>Tester rules checking (TRC)</keyword>
  <keyword>tester resource reporting</keyword>
  <keyword>tester resource targeting</keyword>
  <keyword>tester resource loading</keyword>
</bibdata>