<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain">IEEE Guide Adoption of PMI Standard</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">A Guide to the Project Management Body of Knowledge</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Guide Adoption of PMI Standard - A Guide to the Project Management Body of Knowledge</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/1302773</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 1490-2003 (Revision of IEEE Std 1490-1998)</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-3894-7</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2004.94565</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>1490-2003</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2004-05-24</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2019-04-24</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2003-12-10</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Supersedes IEEE Std 1490-1998 SUMMARY: IEEE Std 1490-2003 is an adoption, in its entirety, of A Guide to Project Management Body of Knowledge (PMBOK&amp;amp;#174; Guide). Project scope: The primary purpose of this document is to identify and describe that subset of the PMBOK that is generally accepted and adopt this as IEEE Std 1490-2002. Generally accepted means that the knowledge and practices described are applicable to most projects most of the time, and that there is widespread consensus about their value and usefulness. Generally accepted does not mean that the knowledge and practices described are or should be applied uniformly on all projects; the project management team is always responsible for determining what is appropriate for any given project. This document is also intended to provide a common lexicon within the profession for talking about project management. Project management is a relatively young profession, and while there is substantial commonality around what is done, there is relatively little commonality in the terms used. Footnote: Project Management Body of Knowledge (PMBOK) and Project Management Institute (PMI) are registered as trademarks of the Project Management Institute, Inc. Project purpose: SESC has previously adopted the 1996 version of PMIBOK to provide a framework for software engineering project management. PMBOK 2000 added new material to reflect the growth of the knowledge and practices in the field of project management by capturing those practices, tools, techniques, and other relevant items that have become generally accepted. Additionally, clarification text and figures, and corrections, have been added that make the document more valuable to users. SESC intends to adopt the current version of PMBOK, replacing the previous version.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2004</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Patents</keyword>
  <keyword>Project management</keyword>
  <keyword>Knowledge engineering</keyword>
  <keyword>Warranties</keyword>
  <keyword>Licenses</keyword>
  <keyword>body of knowledge</keyword>
  <keyword>project</keyword>
  <keyword>project management</keyword>
</bibdata>