<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Trial-Use Guide for Testing Permanent Magnet Machines</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Trial-Use Guide for Testing Permanent Magnet Machines</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7047988</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 1812-2014</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-9469-1</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2015.7047988</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>1812-2014</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2015-03-13</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2015-02-24</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2015-02-24</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2014-12-10</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Contained in this trial-use guide are instructions for conducting tests to determine the performance characteristics and machine parameters of permanent magnet (PM) machines. The tests described may be applied to motors and generators, as needed, and no attempt is made to partition this guide into clauses applying to motors and clauses applying to generators. It is not intended that this guide shall cover all possible tests, or tests of a research nature, but only those general methods that may be used to obtain the performance data and machine parameters. The schedule of factory and field tests, which may be required on new equipment, is normally specified by applicable standards or by contract specifications. This guide should not be interpreted as requiring any specific test in a given transaction or implying any guarantee as to specific performance indices or operating conditions.The term specified conditions for tests as used in this guide will be considered as rated conditions unless otherwise agreed upon. Rated conditions apply usually to the quantities listed on the machine nameplate.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Contained in this trial-use guide are instructions for conducting tests to determine the performance characteristics and machine parameters of permanent magnet (PM) machines. The tests described may be applied to motors and generators, as needed, and no attempt is made to partition this guide into clauses applying to motors and clauses applying to generators. It is not intended that this guide shall cover all possible tests, or tests of a research nature, but only those general methods that may be used to obtain the performance data and machine parameters. The schedule of factory and field tests, which may be required on new equipment, is normally specified by applicable standards or by contract specifications. This guide should not be interpreted as requiring any specific test in a given transaction or implying any guarantee as to specific performance indices or operating conditions. The term specified conditions for tests as used in this guide will be considered as rated conditions unless otherwise agreed upon. Rated conditions apply usually to the quantities listed on the machine nameplate.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2015</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Committees</keyword>
  <keyword>Testing</keyword>
  <keyword>Permanent magnet machines</keyword>
  <keyword>Accuracy</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE Power &amp;amp; Energy Society</keyword>
  <keyword>characteristics</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE 1812(TM)</keyword>
  <keyword>permanent magnet machines</keyword>
  <keyword>testing</keyword>
</bibdata>