<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain">ISO/IEC/IEEE International Standard</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">Systems and Software Engineering--Life Cycle Management--Part 5: Software Development Planning</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">ISO/IEC/IEEE International Standard - Systems and Software Engineering--Life Cycle Management--Part 5: Software Development Planning</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7955095</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">ISO/IEC/IEEE 24748-5:2017(E)</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-3653-3</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2017.7955095</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>24748-5-2017</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2017-07-07</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2017</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2017-06-22</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2017-05-18</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">ISO/IEC/IEEE 24748 provides unified and consolidated guidance on the life cycle management of systems and software. This document focuses on the processes required for successful planning and management of the project's software development effort and for development of the software development plan (SDP) as a vehicle for representing a project's application of software life cycle processes. The SDP is a top level technical planning document for a project which addresses technical management processes established by three principal sources (the project s contract, applicable organizational and technical management processes, and the software development project team) as necessary to successfully accomplish the software development related tasks of the project.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">ISO/IEC/IEEE 24748 provides unified and consolidated guidance on the life cycle management of systems and software. This document focuses on the processes required for successful planning and management of the project's software development effort and for development of the software development plan (SDP) as a vehicle for representing a project's application of software life cycle processes. The SDP is a top level technical planning document for a project which addresses technical management processes established by three principal sources (the project’s contract, applicable organizational and technical management processes, and the software development project team) as necessary to successfully accomplish the software development related tasks of the project.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2016</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>ISO</name>
      </organization>
    </owner>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>IEC</name>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Software development</keyword>
  <keyword>Product life cycle management</keyword>
  <keyword>Management</keyword>
  <keyword>Planning</keyword>
  <keyword>Software engineering</keyword>
  <keyword>IEC Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>ISO Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Software planning</keyword>
  <keyword>software development plan</keyword>
  <keyword>software life cycle</keyword>
  <keyword>technical management</keyword>
  <keyword>technical planning processes</keyword>
  <keyword>24748</keyword>
</bibdata>