<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Test Procedure for Close-Talking Pressure-Type Microphones</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Test Procedure for Close-Talking Pressure-Type Microphones</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7384635</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE No 258-1965</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-0229-3</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1965.7384635</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>258-1965</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2016-02-03</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1965-01-15</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-01-18</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1965</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">A close-talking pressure-type microphone is anacoustic transducer which is intended for use in close proximity to the lips of the talker and is either hand-held or boom-mounted. Various types of microphonesare currently used for close-talking applications. These include carbon, dynamic, magnetic, piezoelectric, electrostrictive and condenser types. Each of these microphones has only one side of its diaphragm exposed to sound waves, and its electricoutput substantially corresponds to the instantaneoussound pressure of the impressed sound wave. Since a close-talking microphone is used in the near sound field produced by a person's mouth, it is necessary when measuring the performance of such microphones to utilize a sound source which approximates the characteristics of the human sound generator.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">A close-talking pressure-type microphone is anacoustic transducer which is intended for use in closeproximity to the lips of the talker and is eitherhand-held or boom-mounted. Various types of microphonesare currently used for close-talking applications.These include carbon, dynamic, magnetic,piezoelectric, electrostrictive and condenser types.Each of these microphones has only one side of itsdiaphragm exposed to sound waves, and its electricoutput substantially corresponds to the instantaneoussound pressure of the impressed sound wave.Since a close-talking microphone is used in thenear sound field produced by a person's mouth, it isnecessary when measuring the performance of suchmicrophones to utilize a sound source which approximatesthe characteristics of the human sound generator.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1965</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Microphones</keyword>
  <keyword>Pressure measurement</keyword>
  <keyword>Audio systems</keyword>
</bibdata>