<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Test Procedure for Evaluation of Insulation Systems for Electronics Power Transformers</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Test Procedure for Evaluation of Insulation Systems for Electronics Power Transformers</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7393390</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE No 266-1969</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-0237-8</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1969.7393390</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>266-1969</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2016-02-12</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1969</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-01-26</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1969</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">The intent of this Test Procedure is to establish a uniform method by which the life of electronics transformer insulation systems can be compared. Thermal degradation is generally one of the major factors affecting the life of most insulating materials. It was chosen to be the major environmental factor in this Test Procedure. Other environmental factors, such as vibration,thermal shock, and moisture, have been included to simulate operating conditions. These factors have been chosen in such a way as to develop and disclose promptly any significant weaknesses during the temperature aging of an insulation system.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">The intent of this Test Procedure is to establish a uniform method by which the life ofelectronics transformer insulation systems can be compared. Thermal degradation is generallyone of the major factors affecting the life of most insulating materials. It was chosen to be themajor environmental factor in this Test Procedure. Other environmental factors, such as vibration,thermal shock, and moisture, have been included to simulate operating conditions. Thesefactors have been chosen in such a way as to develop and disclose promptly any significantweaknesses during the temperature aging of an insulation system.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1969</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Power transformers</keyword>
  <keyword>Transformers</keyword>
  <keyword>Insulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Power system measurement</keyword>
  <keyword>Power transmission lines</keyword>
  <keyword>insulation</keyword>
  <keyword>evaluation</keyword>
  <keyword>elrctronics</keyword>
  <keyword>transformers</keyword>
  <keyword>test</keyword>
</bibdata>