<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">AIEE Proposed Standard for Guiding Principles for the Selection of Reference Values for Electrical Standards</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">AIEE Proposed Standard for Guiding Principles for the Selection of Reference Values for Electrical Standards</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7407275</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">AIEE No.3-1942</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-0291-0</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1942.7407275</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>3-1942</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2016-03-04</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1942-05-31</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-02-15</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1942</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Test results and general performance of electrical apparatus, conductors and materials frequently are influenced by conditions such as Temperature, Pressure, Altitude, Density and Humidity of the surrounding air or other medium. For comparative results, it is necessary to standardize the conditions under which tests are made or to which test results are corrected. This pamphlet serves as a guide in the preparation or revision of standards for apparatus or materials of specific types or fields of use. If a particular existing standard calls for other provisions, the existing standard should be followed. The values given are not mandatory, but are recommended for use in preference to other values unless there are good technical or economic reasons for using others. The values recommended have in general been selected to agree with well-established practices. Provisions are made for a great variety of conditions and for widely different apparatus and materials, some of which may be of practical importance only under unusual circumstances. In any individual standard, only those quantities of real practical importance in the particular case should be used. When ranges are suggested, it is generally with the thought that acceptance tests may be made within that range. Tests may be made outside the range, if acceptable, and agreed upon correction factors are available. Preferred Numbers are suggested in many cases where there is no established practice.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1942</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>AIEE</name>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>AIEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Electrical equipment</keyword>
  <keyword>Temperature distribution</keyword>
  <keyword>Insulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Surge protection</keyword>
</bibdata>