<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Recommended Practice for Auxiliary Devices for Rotating Electrical Machines in Class I, Division 2 and Zone 2 Locations</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Recommended Practice for Auxiliary Devices for Rotating Electrical Machines in Class I, Division 2 and Zone 2 Locations</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/1488513</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 303-2004 (Revision of IEEE Std 303-1991)</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">0-7381-4106-2</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2004.96279</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>303-2004</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2009-01-15</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2004</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2004-06-24</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This recommended practice applies to the application and installation procedures of auxiliary devices in or on electric rotating machines that are employed in hazardous locations classified as Class 1, Division 2 or Class I Zone 2 under commonly used worldwide regulations. These regulations are: the National Electrical Code (United States); the Canadian Electrical Code, Part 1 (Canada); and combined practices of the International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC), the European Committee for Electrotechnical Standardization (CENELEC), and Standards Australia / Standards New Zealand (AS/NZS). Included is a list of source documents, definitions and nomenclature. Devices include terminal housings, heaters, surge protection, power factor correction capacitors, shaft grounding, and enclosures. Special marking requirements are also discussed</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This recommended practice applies to the application and installation procedures of auxiliary devices in or on electric rotating machines that are employed in hazardous locations classified as Class I, Division 2 or Class I Zone 2 under commonly used worldwide regulations. These regulations are: the National Electrical Code (United States); the Canadian Electrical Code, Part 1 (Canada); and combined practices of the International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC), the European Committee for Electrotechnical Standardization (CENELEC), and Standards Australia / Standards New Zealand (AS/NZS). Included is a list of source documents, definitions and nomenclature. Devices include terminal housings, heaters, surge protection, power factor correction capacitors, shaft grounding, and enclosures. Special marking requirements are also discussed.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2004</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
</bibdata>