<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Digital Intelligence (DQ)--Framework for Digital Literacy, Skills, and Readiness</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Digital Intelligence (DQ)--Framework for Digital Literacy, Skills, and Readiness</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9321783</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 3527.1-2020</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-7050-6</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2021.9321783</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>3527.1-2020</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2021-03-05</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2021-01-15</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2021-01-13</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2020-09-24</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">In today's digital age, technology has a firm grasp on practically every aspect of human life, consequently there is growing cross-sector demand to help individuals build digital competencies such as digital literacy, digital skills, and digital readiness. However, there is no universally accepted meaning of terms like &amp;amp;#x201C;digital literacy,&amp;amp;#x201D; &amp;amp;#x201C;digital skills,&amp;amp;#x201D; or &amp;amp;#x201C;digital readiness,&amp;amp;#x201D; which can lead to difficulty coordinating efforts to improve digital competencies worldwide. Digital Intelligence (DQ) was developed to encompass a comprehensive set of technical, cognitive, meta-cognitive, and socio-emotional competencies, which are grounded in universal moral values and enable individuals to face the challenges of digital life and adapt to its demands. The DQ Framework is comprised of 8 areas of digital life--identity, use, safety, security, emotional intelligence, literacy, communication, and rights--across 3 levels of experience--citizenship, creativity, and competitiveness. The objective of this standard is to establish a DQ global standard that encompasses a common framework to ensure that digital competency building efforts are coordinated globally. It includes a common set of definitions, language, and understanding of digital literacy, skills, and readiness that can be adopted by all stakeholders worldwide, including national governments, the educational industry, the technology industry, international agencies, private companies, and society as a whole.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">In today’s digital age, technology has a firm grasp on practically every aspect of human life, consequently there is growing cross-sector demand to help individuals build digital competencies such as digital literacy, digital skills, and digital readiness. However, there is no universally accepted meaning of terms like “digital literacy,” “digital skills,” or “digital readiness,” which can lead to difficulty coordinating efforts to improve digital competencies worldwide. Digital Intelligence (DQ) was developed to encompass a comprehensive set of technical, cognitive, meta-cognitive, and socio-emotional competencies, which are grounded in universal moral values and enable individuals to face the challenges of digital life and adapt to its demands. The DQ Framework is comprised of 8 areas of digital life--identity, use, safety, security, emotional intelligence, literacy, communication, and rights--across 3 levels of experience--citizenship, creativity, and competitiveness. The objective of this standard is to establish a DQ global standard that encompasses a common framework to ensure that digital competency building efforts are coordinated globally. It includes a common set of definitions, language, and understanding of digital literacy, skills, and readiness that can be adopted by all stakeholders worldwide, including national governments, the educational industry, the technology industry, international agencies, private companies, and society as a whole.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2020</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Digital intelligence</keyword>
  <keyword>Human factors</keyword>
  <keyword>Education</keyword>
  <keyword>community development</keyword>
  <keyword>cyber-health</keyword>
  <keyword>cyber-risk</keyword>
  <keyword>digital citizenship</keyword>
  <keyword>digital competency</keyword>
  <keyword>digital intelligence</keyword>
  <keyword>digital literacy</keyword>
  <keyword>digital readiness</keyword>
  <keyword>digital skills</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE 3527.1</keyword>
  <keyword>future-readiness</keyword>
  <keyword>future skills</keyword>
  <keyword>human capital development</keyword>
  <keyword>skills development</keyword>
  <keyword>technology design</keyword>
  <keyword>technology education</keyword>
</bibdata>