<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Definitions of Terms Used in IEEE Standards on Nuclear Power Generating Stations</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Definitions of Terms Used in IEEE Standards on Nuclear Power Generating Stations</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7409879</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 380-1975 (Revision of IEEE Std 380-1972)</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-0319-1</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1975.7409879</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>380-1975</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2016-03-18</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1975-05-19</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-02-17</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1975</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">All of the terms and definitions in this document have been taken from current IEEE standards on nuclear power generating stations. The source of each definition is indicated by a number in brackets immediately following the definition in Section 1, and full listings of each standard follow in Section 2. As defined herein, the terms are restricted to the manner in which they have been employed in mentioned standards, and the definitions may not, in all cases, be applicable for broader usage. However, because the IEEE standards on nuclear power generating stations have had wide acceptance within both government and industry, the terms, as used in these documents, have come into broad usage by many persons who neither need the standards nor have ready access to them. Since these terms are not included in American National Standard Glossary of Terms in Nuclear Science and Technology, Nl.1-1967, the present document has been published as a convenient method of supplementing that standard.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">All of the terms and definitions in this document have been taken from current IEEE standards on nuclear power generating stations. The source of each definition is indicated by a number in brackets immediately following the definition in Section 1, and full listings of each standard follow in Section 2. As defined herein, the terms are restricted to the manner in which they have been employed in mentioned standards, and the definitions may not, in all cases, be applicable for broader usage. However, because the IEEE standards on nuclear power generating stations have had wide acceptance within both government and industry, the terms, as used in these documents, havecome into broad usage by many persons who neither need the standards nor have ready access tothem. Since these terms are not included in American National Standard Glossary of Terms inNuclear Science and Technology, Nl.1-1967, the present document has been published as a convenient method of supplementing that standard.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1975</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Nuclear power generation</keyword>
  <keyword>Terminology</keyword>
</bibdata>