<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Guide for the Design and Installation of Cable Systems in Power Generating Stations</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Guide for the Design and Installation of Cable Systems in Power Generating Stations</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/29117</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">ANSI/IEEE Std 422-1986</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">0-7381-4207-7</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1986.81604</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>422-1986</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2008-10-24</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1986</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1985-03-21</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This guide provides guidance and recommended practices on the installation and maintenance of liquid-immersed power transformers rated 501 kVA and above with secondary voltages of 1000 V and above. This guide covers the entire range of power transformers, including extra high-voltage (EHV) transformers. This guide does not cover special transformers such as furnace transformers, rectifier transformers, etc. Distinctions are made as required for various MVA ratings, voltage ratings, and types of liquid insulation.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This document has been developed as a guide for the design and installation of wire and cable systems in generating stations with the objective of minimizing failures and their consequences. It applies to both nuclear and nonnuclear electric power generating stations. It covers cable performance, size and voltage rating, electrical segregation, separation of redundant systems, shielding and shield grounding. Cable penetration fire stops, fire detection and extinguishing systems, cable installation, acceptance tests and raceways are also covered.&lt;<etx>&gt;</etx></abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1986</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>Nuclear power generation</keyword>
  <keyword>Power cables</keyword>
  <keyword>Standards</keyword>
</bibdata>