<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Recommended Practice for Electric Installations on Shipboard</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Recommended Practice for Electric Installations on Shipboard</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7421924</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 45-1977 (Revision of IEEE Std 45-1971)</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-0352-8</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1977.7421924</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>45-1977</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2016-05-06</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1977</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-02-29</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1976-12-09</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">These marine recommendations are intended to serve as a guide for the selection and installation of equipment on merchant vessels with electric apparatus for lighting, signaling, communication, power, and propulsion. The recommendations define what are considered good present-day engineering practices with reference to the safety of the personnel and of the ship itself as well as reliability and durability of the apparatus. It is recognized that changes and improvements in shipboard requirements may develop which are not specifically covered herein; such changes, if incorporated in the design, should be equal to the safety and reliability levels defined herein and generally in accord with the text of these standards. Specific IEEE standards are referenced in the text. Other IEEE standards should be followed to the extent applicable. Attention is directed to the fact that regulations for electric installations on shipboard are promulgated by Governmental Regulatory Agencies, the Intergovernmental Maritime Consultative Organization, and Classification Societies. Such regulations have been given due consideration in these recommendations, but there are areas where differences are expressed. Reference should always be made to those regulations which may be applicable to the design.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1977</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <relation type="obsoletedBy">
    <bibitem>
      <formattedref format="text/plain">IEEE Std 45-1983 (revision of ANSI/IEEE Std 45-1977)</formattedref>
    </bibitem>
  </relation>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Marine technology</keyword>
  <keyword>Electric installations</keyword>
  <keyword>Cable installations</keyword>
  <keyword>Terminology</keyword>
</bibdata>