<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Recommended Practice for Installation Design and Installation of Large Lead Storage Batteries for Generating Stations and Substations</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Recommended Practice for Installation Design and Installation of Large Lead Storage Batteries for Generating Stations and Substations</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7425095</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">ANSI/IEEE Std 484-1975</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-0363-4</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1975.7425095</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>484-1975</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2016-03-25</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1975-01-27</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-03-03</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1974-09-05</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Proper installation design and installation procedures are prerequisite to long and reliable serviceof large stationary lead storage batteries. A definite need exists within the industry for recommendations that provide a uniform method for the design of the installation and the installation procedures of all batteries to meet station requirements. However, to provide practices that can be used immediately (especially for nuclear power generating stations), this document will limit its scope to the installation design and installation procedures of large stationary lead storage batteries. Included will be the seismic considerations for new battery installations.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Proper installation design and installation procedures are prerequisite to long and reliable service of large stationary lead storage batteries. A definite need exists within the industry for recommendations that provide a uniform method for the design of the installation and the installation procedures of all batteries to meet station requirements. However, to provide practices that can be used immediately (especially for nuclear power generating stations), this document will limit its scope to the installation design and installation procedures of large stationary lead storage batteries. Included will be the seismic considerations for new battery installations.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1975</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>American National Standards Institute</name>
        <abbreviation>ANSI</abbreviation>
        <uri>https://www.ansi.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Lead batteries</keyword>
  <keyword>Batteries</keyword>
  <keyword>Storage </keyword>
  <keyword>Design methodology</keyword>
  <keyword>Generators</keyword>
  <keyword>Substations</keyword>
</bibdata>