<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard, Test Code, and Recommended Practice for Induction and Dielectric Heating Equipment</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard, Test Code, and Recommended Practice for Induction and Dielectric Heating Equipment</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7430213</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std No 54-1955</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-0389-4</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1955.7430213</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>54-1955</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2016-04-01</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1955</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-03-10</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1955-12-01</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">High-frequency heating equipments divide into two main types: (1) those used for dielectric heating, and(2) those used for induction heating. The induction heating equipments again divide into seven types: (1) commercial power line; (2) rotary generator; (3) mercury-arc-converter; (4) gaseous-tube converter; (5) mercury-hydrogen-spark-gap converter; (6) quenched spark-gap converter; (7) vacuum-tube generator. Dielectric heating equipments in general use a vacuum-tube oscillator as a source of radio-frequency power ranging in frequency from 2 megacycles to hundreds of megacycles. At frequencies above about 200 megacycles,the power is generated by devices other than a conventional vacuum tube, such as a magnetron, Klystron or other microwave device. A dielectric heating generator is normally a high-voltage generator, and application requires high-voltage radio-frequency matching techniques. An induction heating generator is essentially a high-current device operating into very low impedance circuits and sometimes requires transformation in the load circuit to provide the desired heating effect.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">High-frequency heating equipments divide into twomain types: (1) those used for dielectric heating, and(2) those used for induction heating. The induction heatingequipments again divide into seven types: (1) commercialpower line; (2) rotary generator; (3) mercuryarcconverter; (4) gaseous-tube converter; (5) mercuryhydrogenspark-gap converter; (6) quenched spark-gapconverter; (7) vacuum-tube generator.Dielectric heating equipments in general use a vacuumtube oscillator as a source of radio-frequency powerranging in frequency from 2 megacycles to hundreds ofmegacycles. At frequencies above about 200 megacycles,the power is generated by devices other than a conventionalvacuum tube, such as a magnetron, Klystron or othermicrowave device. A dielectric heating generator is normallya high-voltage generator, and application requireshigh-voltage radio-frequency matching techniques. Aninduction heating generator is essentially a high-currentdevice operating into very low impedance circuits andsometimes requires transformation in the load circuit toprovide the desired heating effect.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1955</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Encoding</keyword>
  <keyword>Testing</keyword>
  <keyword>Dielectrics</keyword>
  <keyword>Electromagnetic heating</keyword>
  <keyword>Induction heating</keyword>
</bibdata>