<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IRE Standards on Antennas and Waveguides: Definitions for Waveguide Components, 1955</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IRE Standards on Antennas and Waveguides: Definitions for Waveguide Components, 1955</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7369887</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">55 IRE 2.S1 (IEEE Std No 147)</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-0197-5</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1955.7369887</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>55 IRE 2.S1-1955</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2016-01-22</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1955</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2015-12-31</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1955</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">A set of definitions of basic waveguide terms prepared by the Technical Committee on Antennas and Waveguides was published as IRE Standards in December, 1953 (53 IRE 2. Si). The present Standards on Waveguide Components, Definitions of Terms, represent an extension of the work of this committee from 1953 to 1955. Waveguide component terms have not previously been standardized by the IRE; however, with continuing development in this field the need for such definitions has become increasingly apparent. The present list comprises only the more general, basic and established terms. For example, Waveguide Transformer is defined but the many specific types of waveguide transformer such as Double Stub Transformer, Quarter-Wave Sleeve Transformer, Probe Transformer, Eccentric Line Transformer, and others are not defined. As used in the following definitions, Waveguide is a generic term which includes transmission line and uniconductor wave guides as special cases. For specific definitions see 53 IRE 2. 51.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1955</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>IRE</name>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IRE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Antenna measurements</keyword>
  <keyword>Waveguides</keyword>
  <keyword>Terminology</keyword>
  <keyword>DIctionaries</keyword>
</bibdata>