<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEC/IEEE Test methods for the characterization of organic transistors and materials</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEC/IEEE Test methods for the characterization of organic transistors and materials</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6617657</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEC 62860:2013(E) IEEE Std 1620-2008</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-8685-6</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2013.6617657</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>62860-2013</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2013</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2013-10-02</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2013-10-02</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>Piscataway</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Recommended methods and standardized reporting practices for electrical characterization of printed and organic transistors are covered. Due to the nature of printed and organic electronics, significant measurement errors can be introduced if the electrical characterization design-of-experiment is not properly addressed. This standard describes the most common sources of measurement error, particularly for high-impedance electrical measurements commonly required for printed and organic transistors. This standard also gives recommended practices in order to minimize and/or characterize the effect of measurement artifacts and other sources of error encountered while measuring printed and organic transistors.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2013</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>IEC</name>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEC standards</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Transistors</keyword>
  <keyword>Organic materials</keyword>
  <keyword>Testing</keyword>
  <keyword>Error detection</keyword>
  <keyword>Recommended methods and standardized reporting practices for electricalcharacterization of printed and organic transistors are covered. Due to the nature of printed andorganic electronics</keyword>
  <keyword>significant measurement errors can be introduced if the electricalcharacterization design-of-experiment is not properly addressed. This standard describes themost common sources of measurement error</keyword>
  <keyword>particularly for high-impedance electricalmeasurements commonly required for printed and organic transistors. This standard also givesrecommended practices in order to minimize and/or characterize the effect of measurementartifacts and other sources of error encountered while measuring printed and organic transistors.</keyword>
</bibdata>