<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard Definitions for Use in Reporting Electric Generating Unit Reliability, Availability, and Productivity</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard Definitions for Use in Reporting Electric Generating Unit Reliability, Availability, and Productivity</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4135890</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 762-2006 (Revision of IEEE Std 762-1987)</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-5226-4</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2007.335902</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>762-2006</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2008-02-11</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2007</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-03-21</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2006-09-15</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard provides a methodology for the interpretation of electric generating unit performance data from various systems and to facilitate comparisons among different systems. It also standardizes terminology and indexes for reporting electric generating unit reliability, availability, and productivity performance measures. This standard is intended to aid the electric power industry in reporting and evaluating electric generating unit reliability, availability, and productivity while recognizing the power industry's needs, including marketplace competition. Included are equations for equivalent demand forced outage rate (EFOR<sub>d</sub>), newly identified outage states, discussion of commercial availability, energy weighted equations for group performance indexes, definitions of outside management control (OMC), pooling methodologies, and time-based calculations for group performance indexes.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard provides a methodology for the interpretation of electric generating unit performance data from various systems and to facilitate comparisons among different systems. It also standardizes terminology and indexes for reporting electric generating unit reliability, availability, and productivity performance measures. This standard is intended to aid the electric power industry in reporting and evaluating electric generating unit reliability, availability, and productivity while recognizing the power industry's needs, including marketplace competition. Included are equations for equivalent demand forced outage rate (EFORd), newly identified outage states, discussion of commercial availability, energy weighted equations for groupperformance indexes, definitions of outside management control (OMC), pooling methodologies, and time-based calculations for group performance indexes.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2007</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <relation type="updates">
    <description format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">revises</description>
    <bibitem>
      <formattedref format="text/plain">ANSI/IEEE Std 762-1987</formattedref>
    </bibitem>
  </relation>
  <keyword>available state</keyword>
  <keyword>EFORd</keyword>
  <keyword>equivalent demand forced outage rate</keyword>
  <keyword>forced outage</keyword>
  <keyword>maintenance outage</keyword>
  <keyword>OMC</keyword>
  <keyword>outside management control</keyword>
  <keyword>planned outage</keyword>
  <keyword>pooling methodology</keyword>
  <keyword>transition between active states</keyword>
  <keyword>unavailable state</keyword>
  <keyword>weighted factor</keyword>
</bibdata>