<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Local and Metropolitan Area Networks</title>
  <title type="title-part" format="text/plain">Part 20: Air Interface for Mobile Broadband Wireless Access Systems Supporting Vehicular Mobility -- Physical and Media Access Control Layer Specification</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Local and Metropolitan Area Networks - Part 20: Air Interface for Mobile Broadband Wireless Access Systems Supporting Vehicular Mobility -- Physical and Media Access Control Layer Specification</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4618042</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 802.20-2008</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-5766-5</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2008.4618042</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>802.20-2008</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2009-03-13</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2008-08-29</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2017-07-12</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2008-06-12</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">The technical requirements of this standard form a compatibility standard for mobile broadband wireless access systems. The standard ensures that a compliant access terminal (AT) or user terminal (UT) can obtain service through any access node (AN) or base station (BS) conforming to properly selected modes of this standard, consistent with equipment and operator requirements, thus providing a framework for the rapid development of cost-effective, multivendor mobile broadband wireless access systems. This compatibility standard is targeted for use in a wide variety of licensed frequency bands and regulatory environments.This standard provides for future standardized extension capabilities. The architecture defined by this standard permits such expansion without the loss of backward compatibility.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">These technical requirements of this standard form a compatibility standard for mobile broadband wireless access systems. The requirements standard ensures that a compliant Access Terminal (AT) or User Terminal (UT) can obtain service through any Access Network Node (AN) or Base Station (BS) conforming to properly selected modes of this standard, consistent with equipment and operator requirements, thus providing a framework for the rapid development of cost-effective, interoperable multivendor mobile broadband wireless access systems. This compatibility standard is targeted for use in a wide variety of licensed frequency bands and regulatory environments. This specification standard includes provisions provides for future service additions and expansion of system standardized extension capabilities. The architecture defined by this specification standard permits such expansion without the loss of backward compatibility to older access terminals or user terminals.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2008</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>802.20-2008</keyword>
  <keyword>access node</keyword>
  <keyword>access terminal</keyword>
  <keyword>base station</keyword>
  <keyword>broadband</keyword>
  <keyword>LAN</keyword>
  <keyword>local area networks</keyword>
  <keyword>MAN</keyword>
  <keyword>metropolitan area networks</keyword>
  <keyword>user terminal</keyword>
  <keyword>vehicular mobility</keyword>
  <keyword>wireless access</keyword>
</bibdata>