<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Futurebus+(R) -- Logical Protocol Specification</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Futurebus+(R) -- Logical Protocol Specification</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/159471</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std 896.1-1991</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-4583-9</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1992.101087</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>896.1-1991</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1992</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2019-03-27</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1991-09-26</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">IEEE Std 896.1-1991 provides a set of tools with which to implement a Futurebus+architecture with performance and cost scalability over time, for multiple generations of single- and multiple-bus multiprocessor systems. Although this specification is principally intended for 64-bit address and data operation, a fully compatible 32-bit subset is provided, along with compatible extensions to support 128- and 256-bit data highways. Allocation of bus bandwidth to competing modules is provided by either a fast centralized arbiter, or a fully distributed, one or two pass, parallel contention arbiter. Bus allocation rules are provided to suit the needs of both real-time (priority based) and fairness (equal opportunity access based) configurations. Transmission of data over the multiplexed address/data highway is governed by one of two intercompatible transmission methods: (1) a technology-independent, compelled-protocol, supporting broadcast, broadcall, and transfer intervention (the minimum requirement for all Futurebus+systems), and (2) a configurable transfer-rate, source-synchronized protocol supporting only block transfers and source-synchronized broadcast for systems requiring the highest possible performance.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1992</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>Computer interfaces</keyword>
  <keyword>Protocols</keyword>
  <keyword>Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>bus architecture</keyword>
  <keyword>futurebus+</keyword>
  <keyword>logical protocol</keyword>
  <keyword>multiprocessor systems</keyword>
</bibdata>