<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain">IEEE Recommended Practice for Efficiency Determination of Alternating-Current Adjustable-Speed Drives. Part I</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">Load Commutated Inverter Synchronous Motor Drives</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Recommended Practice for Efficiency Determination of Alternating-Current Adjustable-Speed Drives. Part I - Load Commutated Inverter Synchronous Motor Drives</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/27761</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">ANSI/IEEE Std 995-1987</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">0-7381-4271-9</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1988.80999</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>995-1987</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1988</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1987-03-12</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This recommended practice proposes a method for determining the efficiency of large, adjustable-speed AC motor-drive systems consisting of a load commutated inverter and a synchronous machine, in which a DC-linked converter is connected between the line and the load. This recommended practice is directed primarily to high-capacity systems (exceeding 1000 hp) and drive systems, which normally include equipments such as transformers, reactors, thyristor power converters, and synchronous machines. The method recommends that the existing test standards for the system equipments be used as reference, supplemented by test and calculations include herein to account for operating characteristics of the adjustable-speed drive systems.&lt;<etx>&gt;</etx></abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1988</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>Drives</keyword>
  <keyword>Inverters</keyword>
  <keyword>Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Synchronous motors</keyword>
</bibdata>