<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for the Testing of Overhead Transmission and Distribution Line Hardware</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for the Testing of Overhead Transmission and Distribution Line Hardware</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/661543</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std C135.61-1997(R2006)</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-0388-4</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1998.86154</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>C135.61-1997</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2008-03-17</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2006-12-05</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1997-09-16</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Requirements for mechanically testing load-rated line hardware for use on transmission and distribution facilities are described. Items specifically addressed in this standard include clevis and eye fittings, Y-clevis fittings, socket fittings, ball fittings, chain links, shackles, triangular and rectangular yoke plates, suspension clamps, and strain clamps. This standard is intended to cover routine acceptance testing. It is not intended for initial design tests.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Requirements for mechanically testing load-rated line hardware for use on transmission and distribution facilities are described. Items specifically addressed in this standard include clevis and eye fittings, Y-clevis fittings, socket fittings, ball fittings, chain links, shackles, triangular and rectangular yoke plates, suspension clamps and strain clamps. This standard is intended to cover routine acceptance testing. It is not intended for initial design tests.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1998</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>Power system measurements</keyword>
</bibdata>