<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">National Electrical Safety Code 2007 Edition</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">National Electrical Safety Code 2007 Edition</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4116784</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std C2-2007</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-9828-6</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2006.322219</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>C2-2007</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2006-08-01</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2015-10-19</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2006</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard covers basic provisions for safeguarding of persons from hazards arising from the installation, operation, or maintenance of 1) conductors and equipment in electric supply stations, and 2) overhead and underground electric supply and communication lines. It also includes work rules for the construction, maintenance, and operation of electric supply and communication lines and equipment. The standard is applicable to the systems and equipment operated by utilities, or similar systems and equipment, of an industrial establishment or complex under the control of qualified persons. This standard consists of the introduction, definitions, grounding rules, list of referenced and bibliographic documents, and Parts 1, 2, 3, and 4 of the 2007 Edition of the National Electrical Safety Code.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2006</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>Safety</keyword>
  <keyword>NIST</keyword>
  <keyword>Grounding</keyword>
  <keyword>Trademarks</keyword>
  <keyword>Consumer electronics</keyword>
  <keyword>communications industry safety; construction of communication lines; construction of electric supply lines; electrical safety; electric supply stations; electric utility stations; high-voltage safety; operation of communications sys­tems; operation of electric supply systems; power station equipment; power station safety; public utility safety; safety work rules; underground communication line safety; underground electric line safety.</keyword>
</bibdata>