<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE standard for preferred ratings, related requirements, and application recommendations for low-voltage AC (635 V and below) and DC (3200 V and below) power circuit breakers</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE standard for preferred ratings, related requirements, and application recommendations for low-voltage AC (635 V and below) and DC (3200 V and below) power circuit breakers</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5071561</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std C37.16-2009</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-5941-6</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2009.5071561</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>C37.16</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2009-06-26</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2009</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2008-03-19</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard defines the preferred ratings for low-voltage ac (635 V and below) power circuit breakers, general purpose dc (325 V and below) power circuit breakers, heavy duty low- voltage dc (3200 V and below) power circuit breakers, and fused (integrally or non-integrally) low- voltage ac (600 V and below) power circuit breakers.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard defines the preferred ratings for low-voltage ac (635 V and below) power circuit breakers, general purpose dc (325 V and below) power circuit breakers, heavy duty lowvoltage dc (3200 V and below) power circuit breakers, and fused (integrally or non-integrally) lowvoltage ac (600 V and below) power circuit breakers.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2009</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>dc power circuit breaker; integrally fused low-voltage ac power circuit breaker; low-voltage; non-integrally fused low-voltage ac power circuit breaker; power circuit breaker</keyword>
</bibdata>