<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard Specifications for High-Voltage Expulsion, Current-Limiting, and Combination-Type Distribution and Power Class External Fuses, with Rated Voltages from 1 kV through 38 kV, Used for the Protection of Shunt Capacitors</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard Specifications for High-Voltage Expulsion, Current-Limiting, and Combination-Type Distribution and Power Class External Fuses, with Rated Voltages from 1 kV through 38 kV, Used for the Protection of Shunt Capacitors</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4581388</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std C37.43-2008</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-5780-1</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2008.4581388</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>C37.43-2008</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2008-10-17</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2008</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2017-06-07</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2008-06-12</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Specifications for high-voltage (above 1000 V) distribution and power class expulsion, current-limiting, and combination-type external capacitor fuses and accessories, with rated voltages from 1 kV through 38 kV, for protecting shunt capacitors complying with IEEE Std 18-2002 and NEMA CP 1-2000, are established in this standard. All of these devices are intended for use on AC systems. These fuses may be used with capacitor units, groups of units, or entire capacitor banks.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard establishes specifications for high-voltage (above 1000 V) distribution and power class expulsion, current-limiting, and combination-type external capacitor fuses and accessories, with rated voltages from 1 kV through 38 kV, for protecting shunt capacitors complying with IEEE Std 18-2002 and NEMA CP 1-2000. All of these devices are intended for use on ac systems. These fuses may be used with capacitor units, groups of units, or entire banks and include specific capacitor line [group] and capacitor unit fuse types as follows: a) Current-limiting fuses; b) Expulsion fuses; c) Combination of current-limiting and expulsion fuses; d) Fuse supports, fuse mountings, and accessories used with fuses of type a), type b), and type c); and e) Current-limiting, expulsion, and combination-type capacitor fuses [type a), type b), and type c), respectively] used in fuse enclosure packages (FEPs). (Superseded by IEEE C37.42-2016.)</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2008</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Fuses</keyword>
  <keyword>Capacitors</keyword>
  <keyword>Switchgear</keyword>
  <keyword>Trademarks</keyword>
  <keyword>Patents</keyword>
  <keyword>C37.43-2008</keyword>
  <keyword>current-limiting fuses</keyword>
  <keyword>distribution class fuses</keyword>
  <keyword>expulsion fuses</keyword>
  <keyword>fuse</keyword>
  <keyword>fuse applications</keyword>
  <keyword>fuse enclosure packages</keyword>
  <keyword>high-voltage fuses</keyword>
  <keyword>power class fuses</keyword>
  <keyword>shunt capacitor</keyword>
</bibdata>