<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Guide for Application of Digital Line Current Differential Relays Using Digital Communication</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Guide for Application of Digital Line Current Differential Relays Using Digital Communication</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7181615</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std C37.243-2015</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-9777-7</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2015.7181615</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>C37.243-2015</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2015-08-21</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2015-08-07</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2015-08-06</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2015-06-11</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">A comprehensive guide to practical line current differential schemes using digital communications. Operating principles, synchronization methods, channel requirements, current transformer requirements, external time reference requirements, backup considerations, testing considerations, and troubleshooting are included. This guide also provides specific guidelines for various application aspects including multi-terminal lines, series compensated lines, mutually coupled lines, line charging current, in-zone transformers and reactors, single-phase tripping and reclosing, as well as communications channel requirements.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">A comprehensive guide to practical line current differential schemes using digitalcommunications. Operating principles, synchronization methods, channel requirements, currenttransformer requirements, external time reference requirements, backup considerations, testingconsiderations, and troubleshooting are included. This guide also provides specific guidelines forvarious application aspects including multi-terminal lines, series compensated lines, mutuallycoupled lines, line charging current, in-zone transformers and reactors, single-phase tripping andreclosing, as well as communications channel requirements.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2015</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Synchronization</keyword>
  <keyword>Relays</keyword>
  <keyword>Digital line current differential relays </keyword>
  <keyword>Digital systems</keyword>
  <keyword>alpha plane</keyword>
  <keyword>charge comparison</keyword>
  <keyword>current differential line protection</keyword>
  <keyword>current differential operating methods</keyword>
  <keyword>current ration plane</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE C37.243(TM)</keyword>
  <keyword>percentage differential</keyword>
  <keyword>ping-pong methods</keyword>
  <keyword>time synchronization</keyword>
</bibdata>