<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Guide for Power System Protection Testing</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Guide for Power System Protection Testing</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5352213</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Std C37.233-2009</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-6081-8</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2009.5352213</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>C37.233-2009</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2010-01-08</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2009-12-11</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2019-05-29</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2009-09-11</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Test approaches and procedures for the components and the overall protection and control system functions are presented. Test of equipment in the system protection scheme, associated communications equipment, auxiliary power supplies, and the control of power apparatus are addressed. Much of the testing emphasizes a bottom-up approach, in which the basic behavior of scheme components are verified first, followed by testing of interconnected components in a function-oriented assembly.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This guide covers suggested test requirements for power system protection scheme testing, system application tests, the scope and level of tests based on the application, and benefits of the overall protective schemes testing. This guide encompasses overall system testing procedures (generators, line, line reactors, transformer, capacitors, special protection schemes, end-to-end testing, distributed application within substation, etc.) and data collection requirements, as well as the test procedure definitions. This guide describes the methods, extent, and types of system tests for protection applications at various voltage levels. Control functions inherent to the protective systems are included. Importance of line testing, indirect trip applications, open/closed-loop tests, and dynamic/nonlinear tests are also covered.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2009</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Testing</keyword>
  <keyword>Power system protection</keyword>
  <keyword>Power system relaying</keyword>
  <keyword>Trademarks</keyword>
  <keyword>Patents</keyword>
  <keyword>C37.232-2009</keyword>
  <keyword>application testing</keyword>
  <keyword>commissioning testing</keyword>
  <keyword>design testing</keyword>
  <keyword>maintenance testing</keyword>
  <keyword>performance assessment</keyword>
</bibdata>