<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Metal-Enclosed Interrupter Switchgear</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Standard for Metal-Enclosed Interrupter Switchgear</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/26612</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">ANSI/IEEE Std C37.20.3-1987</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-1056-1</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.1987.79652</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>C37.20.3-1987</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2013-11-08</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>1987</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2019-04-05</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1983-09-22</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard covers metal-enclosed interrupter switchgear assemblies containing but not limited to such devices as interrupter/switches, selector switches, power fuses, control, instrumentation and metering, and protective equipment. It includes, but is not specifically limited to, equipment for the control and protection of apparatus used for distribution of electrical power. This standard is concerned with enclosed, rather than open, switchgear assemblies rated above 1000 V. It includes equipments that are part of primary and secondary unit substations. It does not include gas insulated substation equipments, nor switching devices mounted integrally within a transformer enclosure. In this standard the metal-enclosed interrupter switchgear shall be called MEI switchgear.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">The standard covers metal-enclosed interrupter switchgear assemblies containing such devices as interrupter/switches, selector switches, power fuses and protective equipment. It is concerned with enclosed, rather than open, switchgear assemblies rated above 1000 V used for the distribution of electrical power. It includes equipment that is part of primary and secondary unit substations.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1987</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>Fuses</keyword>
  <keyword>Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Substations</keyword>
  <keyword>Switchgear</keyword>
  <keyword>Interrupters</keyword>
  <keyword>substations</keyword>
  <keyword>switchgear assemblies</keyword>
</bibdata>