<reference anchor="IEEE.C57.12.10-2017" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8360791">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Standard Requirements for Liquid-Immersed Power Transformers</title>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.1109/IEEESTD.2018.8360791"/>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2018" month="May" day="17"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Power transformers</keyword>
    <keyword>Immersion cooling</keyword>
    <keyword>Liquid cooling</keyword>
    <keyword>Voltage control</keyword>
    <keyword>Switchgear</keyword>
    <keyword>Substations</keyword>
    <keyword>dimensional characteristics</keyword>
    <keyword>electrical characteristics</keyword>
    <keyword>IEEE C57.12.10</keyword>
    <keyword>jacking</keyword>
    <keyword>lifting</keyword>
    <keyword>mechanical characteristics</keyword>
    <keyword>on-load tap changer</keyword>
    <keyword>power transformer</keyword>
    <keyword>single-phase</keyword>
    <keyword>three-phase</keyword>
    <abstract>This voluntary consensus standard sets forth the requirements for power transformer application. This standard is intended to be used as a basis for performance, interchangeability, and safety of the equipment covered, and to assist in the proper selection of such equipment. This document is a product standard that covers certain electrical, dimensional, and mechanical characteristics of 50 Hz and 60 Hz, liquid-immersed power transformers and autotransformers. Such power transformers may be remotely or integrally associated with either primary switchgear or substations, or both, for step-down or step-up purposes and base rated as follows: 833 kVA and above single-phase, 750 kVA and above three-phase.This standard applies to all liquid-immersed power transformers and autotransformers that do not belong to the following types of apparatus: instrument transformers, step voltage and induction voltage regulators, arc-furnace transformers, rectifier transformers, specialty transformers, grounding transformers, mobile transformers, and mine transformers.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>