<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Guide for the Application of Surge Protective Devices for Low Voltage (1000 Volts or Less) AC Power Circuits</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Guide for the Application of Surge Protective Devices for Low Voltage (1000 Volts or Less) AC Power Circuits</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4290724</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">C62.72-2007</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-5538-8</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEEStd.2007.4290724</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>C62.72-2007</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2016-07-29</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2007-08-03</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-07-08</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2007-03-08</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Information is provided to specifiers and users of surge-protective devices (SPDs) about the application considerations of SPDs associated with power distribution systems within North America. This guide applies to SPDs to be connected to the load side of the service entrance main overcurrent protective device of 50 Hz or 60 Hz ac power circuits rated at 100V to 1000 V rms. The effects and side effects on the presence and operation of SPDs in low-voltage power distribution systems are described. The coordination of multiple SPDs on the same circuit is described.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Information is provided to specifiers and users of surge-protective devices (SPDs) about the application considerations of SPDs associated with power distribution systems within North America. This guide applies to SPDs to be connected to the load side of the service entrance main over current protective device of 50 Hz or 60 Hz ac power circuits rated at 100&amp;amp;#8211;1000 V rms. The effects and side effects on the presence and operation of SPDs in low-voltage power distribution systems are described. The coordination of multiple SPDs on the same circuit is described.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2007</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Trademarks</keyword>
  <keyword>Surge protection</keyword>
  <keyword>Patents</keyword>
  <keyword>Power engineering</keyword>
  <keyword>Surges</keyword>
  <keyword>lightning protection</keyword>
  <keyword>surge protection coordination</keyword>
  <keyword>surge-protective device</keyword>
</bibdata>