<reference anchor="IEC/IEEE 62704-3.2017" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8089724">
  <front>
    <title>Determining the peak spatial-average specific absorption rate (SAR) in the human body from wireless communications devices, 30 MHz to 6 GHz - Part 3: Specific requirements for using the finite difference time domain (FDTD) method for SAR calculations of mobile phones</title>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.1109/IEEESTD.2017.8089724"/>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2017" month="October" day="28"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>IEC Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Biomedical monitoring</keyword>
    <keyword>Solid modeling</keyword>
    <keyword>Finite difference methods</keyword>
    <keyword>Time-domain analysis</keyword>
    <keyword>Specific absorption rate</keyword>
    <keyword>Biomedical measurements</keyword>
    <abstract>This part of IEC/IEEE 62704 defines the concepts, techniques, benchmark phone models, validation procedures, uncertainties and limitations of the finite difference time domain (FDTD) technique when used for determining the peak spatial-average specific absorption rate (SAR) in standardized head and body phantoms exposed to the electromagnetic fields generated by wireless communication devices, in particular pre-compliance assessment of mobile phones, in the frequency range from 30 MHz to 6 GHz. It recommends and provides guidance on the numerical modelling of mobile phones and benchmark results to verify the general approach for the numerical simulations of such devices. It defines acceptable modelling requirements, guidance on meshing and test positions of the mobile phone and the phantom models. This document does not recommend specific SAR limits since these are found in other documents, e.g. IEEE C95.1-2005[1]2 and ICNIRP[2].</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>