<reference anchor="IEC/IEEE P62704-3/D-2" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7524647">
  <front>
    <title>IEC/IEEE Draft International Standard - Determining the Peak Spatial-Average Specific Absorption Rate (SAR) in the Human Body from Wireless Communications Devices, 30 MHz - 6 GHz Part 3: Specific Requirements for using the Finite Difference Time Domain (FDTD) Method for SAR Calculations of Mobile Phones</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2016" month="July" day="28"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Human factors</keyword>
    <keyword>Wireless communication</keyword>
    <keyword>Peak to average power ratio</keyword>
    <keyword>Specific absorption rate</keyword>
    <keyword>Finite difference methods</keyword>
    <keyword>Time-domain analysis</keyword>
    <keyword>Mobile handsets</keyword>
    <keyword>C95.1</keyword>
    <keyword>ICINRP</keyword>
    <keyword>human body</keyword>
    <keyword>wireless communication</keyword>
    <abstract>This International Standard IEC/IEEE 62704-3 describes the concepts, techniques, benchmark phone models, validation procedures, uncertainties and limitations of the finite difference time domain (FDTD) technique when used for determining the peak spatial-average specific absorption rate (SAR) in standardized head and body phantoms exposed to the electromagnetic fields generated by wireless communication devices, in particular mobile phones, in the frequency range from 30 MHz to 6 GHz. It recommends and provides guidance on the numerical modeling of mobile phones and benchmark results to verif y the general approach for the numerical simulations of such devices. It defines acceptable modeling requirements, guidance on meshing and test positions of the mobile phone and the phantom models. This document will not recommend specific SAR limits since these are found in other documents, e.g., IEEE C95.1-2005[1] and ICNIRP[2].</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>