<reference anchor="IEC/IEEE.P62704-3/D-1.0.2013-05" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6562737">
  <front>
    <title>IEC/IEEE Draft Standard for Determining the Peak Spatial-Average Specific Absorption Rate (SAR) in the Human Body from Wireless Communications Devices, 30 MHz - 6 GHz. Part 3: Specific Requirements for Finite Difference Time Domain (FDTD) Modeling of Mobile Phones/Personal Wireless Devices</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">IEEE</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2013" month="July" day="17"/>
    <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Specific absorption rate</keyword>
    <keyword>Biomedical measurement</keyword>
    <keyword>Human factors</keyword>
    <keyword>Mobile communication</keyword>
    <keyword>Handheld devices</keyword>
    <keyword>Wireless networks</keyword>
    <keyword>C95.1</keyword>
    <keyword>ICINRP</keyword>
    <keyword>human body</keyword>
    <keyword>wireless communication</keyword>
    <abstract>This International Standard IEC/IEEE 62704-3 describes the concepts, techniques, phone models, validation procedures, uncertainties and limitations of the finite difference time domain (FDTD) technique when used for determining the peak spatial-average specific absorption rate (SAR) in standardized human anatomical models exposed to the electromagnetic fields generated by the personal wireless communication devices, in particular handheld mobile phones, in the frequency range from 30 MHz to 6 GHz. It recommends and provides guidance on the numerical modeling of mobile wireless communication devices and benchmark data to verify the numerical simulations of such devices. It defines acceptable modeling requirements, guidance on meshing and test positions of the anatomical models. This document will not recommend specific SAR limits since these are found in other documents, e.g., IEEE C95.1-2005 and ICNIRP.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>