<reference anchor="IEEE.PC95-7/D-11.2014-03" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6781524">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Approved Draft Recommended Practice for Radio Frequency Safety Programs, 3 kHz to 300 GHz</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">IEEE</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2014" month="April" day="1"/>
    <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Radio frequency</keyword>
    <keyword>Electrical safety</keyword>
    <keyword>Electromagnetic interference</keyword>
    <keyword>Radiation exposure</keyword>
    <keyword>Monitoring</keyword>
    <keyword>Access control</keyword>
    <keyword>Safety</keyword>
    <keyword>access restriction</keyword>
    <keyword>electromagnetic exposure</keyword>
    <keyword>electromagnetic fields (EMF)</keyword>
    <keyword>exposure assessment</keyword>
    <keyword>exposure categorization</keyword>
    <keyword>IEEE C95.7(TM)</keyword>
    <keyword>non-ionizing radiation (NIR)</keyword>
    <keyword>personal monitors</keyword>
    <keyword>personal protective equipment (PPE)</keyword>
    <keyword>radio frequency (RF)</keyword>
    <keyword>radio frequency safety program (RFSP)</keyword>
    <keyword>RF awareness training</keyword>
    <keyword>RF exposure</keyword>
    <keyword>RF protection</keyword>
    <keyword>RF safety committee</keyword>
    <keyword>RF safety officer</keyword>
    <keyword>signage</keyword>
    <abstract>Elements of a radio frequency (RF) exposure safety program that provide reasonable and adequate guidance for preventing exposures in excess of recognized limits to electromagnetic fields from RF sources that operate in the frequency range of 3 kHz to 300 GHz are described in IEEE Std C95.7(TM)-2014. The means for accomplishing this are classifying exposure locations into one of four categories based on the potential hazard, as defined by exposure limits, and specifying appropriate controls for each category. Such controls include engineering and administrative controls as well as the use of personal protective equipment, placement of appropriate RF safety signage, designation of restricted access areas, the use of personal RF monitors, and RF safety awareness training. These recommendations are not intended to apply to the purposeful exposure of patients by or under the direction of medical practitioners, but can be used in the development of safety programs for medical staff and otherre persons working with or incidentally exposed to RF fields, and for those wearing implanted or external medical electronic devices. Although designed to complement IEEE Std C95.1(TM), this recommended practice may also be used for the development of programs to ensure conformance with otherre guidelines, standards, or regulations for controlling human exposure to electromagnetic energy as well as IEEE Std C95.6(TM) in which case, appropriate modifications will be necessary to address the low frequency region addressed by IEEE Std C95.6(TM). (The PDF of this standards is available at no charge thru the "IEEE Get Program" http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/servlet/opac?punumber=6874472)</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>