<reference anchor="IEEE PC37-20-1/D-6.0.2015-01" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7024891">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Approved Draft Standard for Metal-Enclosed Low Voltage (1000Vac and Below, 3200Vdc and Below) Power Circuit Breaker Switchgear</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2015" month="January" day="28"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Circuit breakers</keyword>
    <keyword>Outdoor communication</keyword>
    <keyword>Current transformers</keyword>
    <keyword>Transformers</keyword>
    <keyword>Indoor communication</keyword>
    <keyword>Meter reading</keyword>
    <keyword>Switchgear</keyword>
    <keyword>Load management</keyword>
    <keyword>circuit breaker</keyword>
    <keyword>control</keyword>
    <keyword>cumulative loading</keyword>
    <keyword>current transformers</keyword>
    <keyword>drawout</keyword>
    <keyword>IEEE C37.20.1</keyword>
    <keyword>indoor</keyword>
    <keyword>instrumentation</keyword>
    <keyword>load current-carrying</keyword>
    <keyword>metering</keyword>
    <keyword>metal-enclosed</keyword>
    <keyword>outdoor</keyword>
    <keyword>protection</keyword>
    <keyword>stationary</keyword>
    <keyword>switchgear</keyword>
    <abstract>Low-voltage metal-enclosed switchgearwhich contains either stationary or drawout, manually or electrically operated low-voltage ac or dc power circuit breakers in individual metal compartments, in three-pole, four-pole, two-pole, or single-pole constructionis covered. Rated maximum voltage levels are 254 V, 508 V, or 635 V, 730 V, or 1058 V ac and 300/325 V, 600 V, 800 V, 1000 V, 1200 V, 1500 V, 1600 V, or 3200 V dc. The preferred continuous current ratings of the main bus in ac designs are 1600 A, 2000 A, 3000 A, 3200 A, 4000 A, 5000 A, 6000 A, 8000 A, or 10,000A. For dc designs, the preferred ratings are 1600 A, 2000 A, 2500 A, 3000 A, 4000 A, 5000 A, 6000 A, 8000 A, 10 000 A, or 12 000 A. The switchgear may also contain associated control, instruments, metering, protective, and regulating devices as necessary. The standard deals with service conditions, ratings, temperature limitations, and classification of insulating materials, insulation (dielectric) withstand voltage requirements, test procedures, and application.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>