<reference anchor="IEEE PC37-42/D-12.2016-04" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7501438">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Approved Draft Standard Specifications for High-Voltage (&amp;#x003E;1000 V) Fuses and Accessories</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Piscataway</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2016" month="June" day="28"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Fuses</keyword>
    <keyword>Voltage control</keyword>
    <keyword>Switching systems</keyword>
    <keyword>Shunt capacitors</keyword>
    <keyword>Power distribution</keyword>
    <keyword>Current limiters</keyword>
    <keyword>expulsion fuses</keyword>
    <keyword>Class A fuses</keyword>
    <keyword>distribution class fuses</keyword>
    <keyword>high-voltage fuses</keyword>
    <keyword>fuse</keyword>
    <keyword>fuse49 applications</keyword>
    <keyword>fuse disconnecting switches</keyword>
    <keyword>distribution fuse cutouts</keyword>
    <keyword>fuse links</keyword>
    <keyword>current-limiting fuses</keyword>
    <keyword>fuse enclosure packages</keyword>
    <keyword>Class B fuses</keyword>
    <keyword>power class fuses</keyword>
    <keyword>fuses for the protection of shunt capacitors</keyword>
    <keyword>distribution and power class current-limiting fuses</keyword>
    <keyword>fuse hooks</keyword>
    <keyword>supports and mountings</keyword>
    <keyword>tongs</keyword>
    <abstract>Specifications for high voltage (above 1000 volts) Class A and Class B expulsion and current-limiting fuses. This includes: a) Expulsion type Class A [distribution class] fuses, fuse cutouts, fuse disconnecting switches, their associated fuse links or refill units, disconnecting cutouts, and accessories for these devices with rated voltages from 1 through 38 kV. b) Expulsion type Class B [power class] fuses, fuse disconnecting switches, their associated fuse links or refill units, disconnecting cutouts, and accessories for these devices with rated voltages from 1 through 170 kV. c) Class A and Class B current-limiting fuses and accessories for these devices with rated voltages 1 through 38 kV. d) Distribution and power class expulsion, current-limiting, and combination-type external capacitor fuses and accessories, with rated voltages from 1 kV through 38 kV, for protecting shunt capacitors complying with IEEE Std 18 and NEMA CP 1. e) Any of the above devices used in fuse enclosure packages. f) All of these devices are intended for use on alternating current distribution systems.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>