<reference anchor="IEEE.IEEE 1625.2008 Redline" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5982066">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Standard for Rechargeable Batteries for Multi-Cell Mobile Computing Devices</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2013" month="August" day="15"/>
    <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Batteries</keyword>
    <keyword>Mobile communication</keyword>
    <keyword>Cellular networks</keyword>
    <keyword>Handset devices</keyword>
    <keyword>Cellular phones</keyword>
    <keyword>Lithium compounds</keyword>
    <keyword>Portable computers</keyword>
    <keyword>1625-2008</keyword>
    <keyword>battery</keyword>
    <keyword>battery pack</keyword>
    <keyword>cell</keyword>
    <keyword>host device</keyword>
    <keyword>lithium-ion (Li-ion)</keyword>
    <keyword>lithium-ion polymer (Li-ion polymer)</keyword>
    <keyword>mobile computing device</keyword>
    <keyword>pack</keyword>
    <keyword>portable computing</keyword>
    <keyword>rechargeable battery</keyword>
    <keyword>rechargeable battery packs</keyword>
    <abstract>This standard establishes criteria for design analysis for qualification, quality, and reliability of rechargeable battery systems for multi-cell mobile computing devices. It also provides methods for quantifying the operational performance of these batteries and their associated management and control systems including considerations for end-user notification. This standard covers rechargeable battery systems for mobile computing. The battery technologies covered are limited to Li-ion and Li-ion polymer, but future versions of this standard may include technologies that are not in general use at present. Also included are: battery pack electrical and mechanical construction; system, pack, and cell level charge and discharge controls; and battery status communications. The following are addressed: qualification process; manufacturing process control; energy capacity and demand management; levels of management and control in the battery systems; and current and planned lithium-based battery chemistries, packaging technologies, and considerations for end-user notification.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>