<reference anchor="IEEE.IEEE P1609-0/D-7.0.2013-08" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6576805">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Draft Guide for Wireless Access in Vehicular Environments (WAVE) - Architecture</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Piscataway</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2013" month="August" day="8"/>
    <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Intelligent vehicles</keyword>
    <keyword>Wireless communication</keyword>
    <keyword>Wireless networks</keyword>
    <keyword>Vehicles</keyword>
    <keyword>Wireless Access in Vehicular Environments</keyword>
    <keyword>Dedicated Short Range Communications</keyword>
    <keyword>WAVE</keyword>
    <keyword>DSRC</keyword>
    <keyword>RSU</keyword>
    <keyword>OBU</keyword>
    <keyword>WSM</keyword>
    <keyword>PSID</keyword>
    <keyword>WSA</keyword>
    <keyword>WSMP</keyword>
    <abstract>This guide describes the Wireless Access in Vehicular Environments (WAVE) architecture and services necessary for WAVE devices to communicate in a mobile vehicular environment. It is meant to be used in conjunction with the family of IEEE 1609 standards as of its publication date. These include This guide describes the Wireless Access in Vehicular Environments (WAVE) architecture and services necessary for WAVE devices to communicate in a mobile vehicular environment. It is meant to be used in conjunction with the family of IEEE 1609 standards as of its publication date. These include IEEE Std 1609.2 Security Services for Applications and Management Messages, IEEE Std 1609.3 Networking Services, IEEE Std 1609.4 Multi-Channel Operation, IEEE Std 1609.11 Over-the-Air Electronic Payment Data Exchange Protocol for Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITS), IEEE Std 1609.12 Identifier Allocations, and IEEE Std 802.11 in operation outside the context of a basic service set.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>