<reference anchor="IEEE.P1052/D-7.2018-07" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8410203">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Draft Guide for the Functional Specifications for Transmission Static Synchronous Compensator (STATCOM) Systems</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">IEEE</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2018" month="July" day="11"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Automatic voltage control</keyword>
    <keyword>Thyristors</keyword>
    <keyword>Switches</keyword>
    <keyword>Inductors</keyword>
    <keyword>Capacitors</keyword>
    <keyword>Reactive power</keyword>
    <keyword>STATCOM</keyword>
    <keyword>functional requirements</keyword>
    <keyword>high voltage power transmission systems</keyword>
    <keyword>IEEE 1052(TM)</keyword>
    <keyword>power system compensation</keyword>
    <keyword>reactive power supply</keyword>
    <keyword>static synchronous compensator (STATCOM)</keyword>
    <keyword>static var compensator (SVC)</keyword>
    <keyword>transient and dynamic stability</keyword>
    <keyword>voltage regulation</keyword>
    <abstract>Assisting users in specifying the functional requirements for transmission static synchronous compensator (STATCOM) systems using forced commutated technology based on voltage sourced converter topologies is the purpose of this guide. These systems may be hybrid,and also incorporate thyristor and mechanically switched inductors and capacitors. Reactive power compensation, voltage regulation and control, transient and dynamic stability, and control and protection are the functions included. Accepted engineering practices for the application of STATCOM systems are presented. Specifications, typical application requirements, engineering studies, main component characteristics, system functions and features, factory testing, commissioning, and operations are covered. Informative annexes that allow users to develop or modify specific clauses to meet the requirements of a particular transmission system application are included.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>