<reference anchor="IEEE.P287-3/D-8.2021-05" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9443052">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Draft Recommended Practice for Precision Coaxial Connectors at RF, Microwave and Millimeter-wave Frequencies - Part 3: Connector Effects, Uncertainty Specifications and Recommendations for Performance</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="May" day="27"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Millimeter wave measurement</keyword>
    <keyword>Connectors</keyword>
    <keyword>Radio frequency</keyword>
    <keyword>Uncertainty</keyword>
    <keyword>Millimeter wave technology</keyword>
    <keyword>Microwave measurement</keyword>
    <keyword>Frequency measurement</keyword>
    <keyword>Metrology</keyword>
    <keyword>Reproducibility of results</keyword>
    <keyword>Coaxial cables</keyword>
    <keyword>instrument grade connector (IGC)</keyword>
    <keyword>metrology grade precision connector (MGC)</keyword>
    <keyword>minimum performance requirement</keyword>
    <keyword>pin and socket connector</keyword>
    <keyword>coaxial connector</keyword>
    <abstract>The IEEE P287 series of documents presents the combined efforts of IEEE P287 Working Group that reflect the knowledge and experience of leading specialists in the development and measurement of precision coaxial connectors for RF, microwave and millimeter-wave frequencies. It presents minimum performance requirements to standardize both hermaphroditic and pin- and socket-type connectors (287.1). It provides recommended electrical and mechanical test procedures for Instrument Grade and Metrology Grade precision connectors (287.2). Recommended reference procedures including connector effects, connector care and cleaning, connector repeatability and reproducibility test procedures, and a color code for connectors are detailed in the third part of the standard (287.3), this document. A bibliography provides a list of pertinent references for measurement techniques used in determining electrical, mechanical, and dimensional parameters for coaxial connectors.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>