<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Guide for the Characterization and Evaluation of Lithium-Based Batteries in Stationary Applications</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Guide for the Characterization and Evaluation of Lithium-Based Batteries in Stationary Applications</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8016466</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE P1679.1/D25, August 2017</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-4345-6</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>IEEE P1679.1/D25, Aug 2017</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2017-01-01</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2017-08-24</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2017</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Guidance for an objective evaluation of lithium-based energy storage technologies by a potential user for any stationary application is provided in this document. IEEE Std 1679-2010, IEEE Recommended Practice for the Characterization and Evaluation of Emerging Energy Storage Technologies in Stationary Applications is to be used in conjunction with this document. Secondary (rechargeable) electro-chemistries with lithium ions as the active species exchanged between the electrodes during charging and discharging are included in the category of lithium-based batteries for the purposes of this document. Lithium-ion, lithium-ion polymer, lithium-metal polymer, and lithium-sulfur batteries are examples of secondary lithium-based batteries. Primary (non-rechargeable) lithium batteries are beyond the scope of this document. A technology description, information on aging and failure modes, a discussion on safety issues, evaluation techniques, and regulatory issues are provided in this document. Sizing, installation, maintenance, and testing techniques are not covered, except insofar as they may influence the evaluation of a lithium-based battery for its intended application.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2017</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Batteries</keyword>
  <keyword>Lithium batteries</keyword>
  <keyword>Performance evaluation</keyword>
  <keyword>battery</keyword>
  <keyword>energy storage</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE 1679.1(TM)</keyword>
  <keyword>li-ion</keyword>
  <keyword>lithium</keyword>
  <keyword>lithium-based</keyword>
  <keyword>lithium-ion</keyword>
  <keyword>lithium-ion polymer</keyword>
  <keyword>lithium-metal polymer</keyword>
  <keyword>lithium-polymer</keyword>
  <keyword>secondary</keyword>
  <keyword>standby service</keyword>
  <keyword>stationary application</keyword>
</bibdata>