<reference anchor="IEEE.P1679-2/D-16.2017-06" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8353818">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Draft Guide for the Characterization and Evaluation of Sodium-Based Batteries in Stationary Applications</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">IEEE</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2018" month="May" day="3"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Batteries</keyword>
    <keyword>Sodium</keyword>
    <keyword>Temperature measurement</keyword>
    <keyword>Energy storage</keyword>
    <keyword>Sulfur</keyword>
    <keyword>Nickel</keyword>
    <keyword>Performance evaluation</keyword>
    <keyword>battery</keyword>
    <keyword>secondary</keyword>
    <keyword>sodium-beta</keyword>
    <keyword>sodium-metal halide</keyword>
    <keyword>sodium-nickel chloride</keyword>
    <keyword>sodium-13 sulfur</keyword>
    <keyword>&amp;#946;’’-alumina ceramic</keyword>
    <keyword>molten salt</keyword>
    <keyword>high temperature battery</keyword>
    <keyword>standby service</keyword>
    <keyword>stationary application</keyword>
    <keyword>energy storage</keyword>
    <abstract>This document provides guidance for evaluation of the characteristics and performance of sodium-beta batteries by a potential user for stationary applications. Information regarding technology description, safety, aging and failure modes, evaluation techniques, and regulatory issues is included in this guide. This document is to be used in conjunction with IEEE Std 1679, IEEE Recommended Practice for the Characterization and Evaluation of Emerging Energy Storage Technologies in Stationary Applications. Sodium-beta batteries include those secondary (rechargeable) electro-chemistries with sodium as the active 8 species exchanged between the electrodes during charging and discharging, and operating above the melting point of sodium. These batteries use a solid beta-alumina electrolyte, typically written as β’'-alumina. Examples of secondary sodium-beta batteries are sodium-metal chloride and sodium-sulfur batteries.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>