<reference anchor="IEEE.P2847/D-3.2021-08" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9526570">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Draft Standard for DC Power Transmission and Communication to DC Loads</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">IEEE</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="August" day="31"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Load management</keyword>
    <keyword>DC machines</keyword>
    <keyword>Power transmission lines</keyword>
    <keyword>Power line communication</keyword>
    <keyword>PLC</keyword>
    <keyword>DC</keyword>
    <keyword>DC power</keyword>
    <keyword>DC power line communication</keyword>
    <keyword>DC power transmission</keyword>
    <keyword>DC loads</keyword>
    <keyword>Differential signal</keyword>
    <keyword>Differential signal communication</keyword>
    <keyword>High power differential signal power line communication</keyword>
    <abstract>This standard defines physical layer and data link layer specifications for power supply and communication over power lines from a DC Power Source to multiple DC loads as specified in IEEE P2847(TM)/D4 2021. Each receiver has its own physical address and is connected to the transmitter through a pair of power lines in a multi-drop bus or tree topology. The transmitter sends the DC Power and the electric signals corresponding to the communication packets including the control command/data for controlling the DC loads and the target address through the power line by electrically changing the voltage of the wires. Each receiver supplies power to the DC loads with the transmitted and voltage-flattened DC power. Each receiver decodes the control command/data and address from electric signals on the power line and uses them for the connected DC loads control if the addresses match. The standard is in compliance with known Electro-Magnetic Compatibility (EMC) regulations</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>