<reference anchor="IEEE.1625.2008" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4657368">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Standard for Rechargeable Batteries for Multi-Cell Mobile Computing Devices</title>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.1109/IEEESTD.2008.4657368"/>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2020" month="February" day="3"/>
    <keyword>1625-2008</keyword>
    <keyword>battery</keyword>
    <keyword>battery pack</keyword>
    <keyword>cell</keyword>
    <keyword>host device</keyword>
    <keyword>lithium-ion (Li-ion)</keyword>
    <keyword>lithium-ion polymer (Li-ion polymer)</keyword>
    <keyword>mobile computing device</keyword>
    <keyword>pack</keyword>
    <keyword>portable computing</keyword>
    <keyword>rechargeable battery</keyword>
    <keyword>rechargeable battery packs</keyword>
    <abstract>This standard guides manufacturers/suppliers in planning and implementing the controls for the design and manufacture of lithium-ion (Li-ion) and lithium-ion polymer (Li-ion polymer) rechargeable battery packs used for multi-cell mobile computing devices. The provisions of this standard work together to define approaches to design, test, and evaluate a cell, battery pack, and host device to mitigate battery system failure. Additionally, this standard provides recommendations for end-user education and communication materials. This approach recommends the interfaces between subsystems (for example, cell, battery pack, host device, power adapter, etc.), and end users are as important to system reliability as is robust subsystem design and testing. This standard, therefore, includes subsystem interface design responsibilities for each subsystem manufacturer/supplier, and it provides messaging and communication provisions for end-user awareness. Therefore, the responsibility for total system reliability is shared between the designers/manufacturers/suppliers of the subsystems and the end user. Compliance to this standard requires adherence to all the provisions of the standard.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>