<reference anchor="IEEE P3002-7/D-11.2017-12" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8301051">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Draft Recommended Practice for Conducting Motor-Starting Studies in Industrial and Commercial Power Systems</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2018" month="February" day="22"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Acceleration</keyword>
    <keyword>Computational modeling</keyword>
    <keyword>Adjustable speed drive</keyword>
    <keyword>Voltage control</keyword>
    <keyword>Industrial power systems</keyword>
    <keyword>Systems modeling</keyword>
    <keyword>Motor drives</keyword>
    <keyword>adjustable speed drive</keyword>
    <keyword>dynamic motor starting</keyword>
    <keyword>IEEE 3002.7</keyword>
    <keyword>motor acceleration</keyword>
    <keyword>motor protection</keyword>
    <keyword>motor reacceleration</keyword>
    <keyword>motor starting</keyword>
    <keyword>reduced-voltage starters</keyword>
    <keyword>soft-starters</keyword>
    <keyword>static motor starting</keyword>
    <keyword>variable frequency drive</keyword>
    <keyword>voltage flicker</keyword>
    <abstract>Activities related to motor-starting studies, including design considerations for new systems, analytical studies for existing systems, as well as operational and model-validation considerations for industrial and commercial power systems are described. Motor-starting analysis includes evaluation of motor-starting current and voltage drop. Accuracy of calculation results primarily relies on system modeling assumptions and methods used. The use of computer-aided analysis software, with a list of desirable capabilities recommended to conduct a modern motor-starting study, is emphasized. Examples of system data requirements and result-analysis techniques are presented. Benefits obtained from motor-starting studies are discussed, and various types of computer-aided motor-starting studies are examined. Data or information required for these studies, as well as the expected results of a motor-starting study effort, are also reviewed.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>