<reference anchor="IEEE.P11073-10103/D-1.05.02.2011-Sept" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6030883">
  <front>
    <title>Standard for Health informatics - Point-of-care medical device communication - Nomenclature - Implantable device, cardiac</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Piscataway</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Informatics</keyword>
    <keyword>Bioinformatics</keyword>
    <keyword>Biomedical equipment</keyword>
    <keyword>Medical services</keyword>
    <keyword>Cardiology</keyword>
    <keyword>Biomedical monitoring</keyword>
    <keyword>Codes</keyword>
    <keyword>Implantable Devices</keyword>
    <keyword>Medical Device Communication</keyword>
    <keyword>Nomenclature</keyword>
    <keyword>Pacemaker</keyword>
    <keyword>ICD (Implantable Cardioverter Defibrillator)</keyword>
    <keyword>CRT (Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy)</keyword>
    <keyword>Follow-up</keyword>
    <keyword>Remote Follow-up</keyword>
    <keyword>Home Monitoring</keyword>
    <keyword>Remote Monitoring</keyword>
    <keyword>Terminology</keyword>
    <abstract>This project extends the base nomenclature provided in IEEE 11073 tosupport terminology for implantable cardiac devices. Devices within the scope of this nomenclature are implantable pacemakers, defibrillators, devices for cardiac resynchronization therapy, or cardiac monitors. This nomenclature defines the discrete terms necessary to convey a clinically relevant summary of the information obtained during a device interrogation.To improve workflow efficiencies cardiology and electrophysiology practices require the management of summary interrogation information from all vendor devices and systems in a central system such as an Electronic Health Record system or a device clinic management system. To address this requirement, the Implantable Device Cardiac (IDC) Nomenclature defines a standard-based terminology for device data. The nomenclature facilitates the transfer of data from the vendor proprietary systems to the clinic EHR or device clinic management system.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>