<reference anchor="IEEE.ISO/IEC/IEEE 31320-2.2012" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6357338">
  <front>
    <title>ISO/IEC/IEEE International Standard</title>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.1109/IEEESTD.2012.6357338"/>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2012" month="November" day="20"/>
    <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Computer languages</keyword>
    <keyword>Modeling</keyword>
    <keyword>Information technollgy</keyword>
    <keyword>Sematics</keyword>
    <keyword>enterprise</keyword>
    <keyword>functional modeling language</keyword>
    <keyword>IDEF0</keyword>
    <keyword>IEEE 1320.2</keyword>
    <keyword>language</keyword>
    <keyword>modeling language</keyword>
    <keyword>conceptual schema</keyword>
    <keyword>data model</keyword>
    <keyword>IDEF1X</keyword>
    <keyword>IDEF1X97</keyword>
    <keyword>identity style</keyword>
    <keyword>information model</keyword>
    <keyword>keymodel style</keyword>
    <keyword>object</keyword>
    <abstract>IDEF1X<sub>97</sub> consists of two conceptual modeling languages. The key-style language supports data/information modeling and is downward compatible with the US government's 1993 standard, FIPS PUB 184. The identity-style language is based on the object model with declarative rules and constraints. IDEF1X<sub>97</sub> identity style includes constructs for the distinct but related components of object abstraction: interface, requests, and realization; utilizes graphics to state the interface; and defines a declarative, directly executable Rule and Constraint Language for requests and realizations. IDEF1X<sub>97</sub> conceptual modeling supports implementation by relational databases, extended relational databases, object databases, and object programming languages. IDEF1X<sub>97</sub> is formally defined in terms of first order logic. A procedure is given whereby any valid IDEF1X<sub>97</sub> model can be transformed into an equivalent theory in first order logic. That procedure is then applied to a meta model of IDEF1X<sub>97</sub> to define the valid set of IDEF1X<sub>97</sub> models.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>