<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">American National Standard for High Voltage Connectors for Nuclear Instruments</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">American National Standard for High Voltage Connectors for Nuclear Instruments</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6654241</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">ANSI Std N42.4-1971</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-0751-6</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2013.6654241</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>N42.4-1971</docnumber>
  <date type="updated">
    <on>2014-01-17</on>
  </date>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2013-11-01</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2013-11-04</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>1971-04-12</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Coaxial high-voltage connectors on nuclear instruments for DC applications up to 5000 V and AC applications up to 3500 V rms at 60 Hz are covered. The connectors may also be used at higher frequencies provided the operating voltage is appropriately reduced to provide for interchangeability of safe high-voltage connectors in nuclear instrument applications. The connectors are safe in that the pin and socket contacts are well and securely recessed in the connector housing so that hand or body contact of the unmated connector with rated voltage applied will not result in electrical shock. You will receive an email from Customer Service with the URL needed to access this publication online.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Coaxial high-voltage connectors on nuclear instruments for dc applications up to 5000 V and ac applications up to 3500 V rms at 60 Hz are covered. The connectors may also be used at higher frequencies provided the operating voltage is appropriately reduced to provide for interchangeability of safe high-voltage connectors in nuclear instrument applications. The connectors are safe in that the pin and socket contacts are well and securely recessed in the connector housing so that hand or body contact of the unmated connector with rated voltage applied will not result in electrical shock. You will receive an email from Customer Service with the URL needed to access this publication online.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>1971</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>ANSI standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Connectors</keyword>
  <keyword>Instruments</keyword>
  <keyword>Nuclear Instruments</keyword>
  <keyword>Consumer electronics</keyword>
  <keyword>Voltage control</keyword>
  <keyword>Nuclear measurements</keyword>
  <keyword>Connectors</keyword>
</bibdata>