<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain">Electrical Safety Manual for Power and Communications Industries [Adapted from the 2017 IEEE NESC(R) Handbook Premier Edition]</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">Chinese Edition</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">Electrical Safety Manual for Power and Communications Industries [Adapted from the 2017 IEEE NESC(R) Handbook Premier Edition] - Chinese Edition</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8844364</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">Electrical Safety Manual for Power and Communications Industries [Adapted from the 2017 IEEE NESC(R) Handbook Premier Edition] - Chinese Edition</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-5722-4</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.1109/IEEESTD.2019.8844364</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>NESC HBK</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2019</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2019-09-18</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2019</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This handbook, in its Chinese version, is essential for Chinese speaking communities and assist in areas that need well-defined regulations related to electrical safety for power, energy transmission and distribution, and communications industries. Important to power and energy engineers, as well as to communications providers, such as internet, phone et al. The handbook includes text directly from the NESC 2017 edition, which provides users an easy reference back to the code, ruling-by-ruling, all in Chinese; plus, subject matter expert commentary also in Chinese. It gives users insight into what lies behind the NESC's rules and how to apply them. The Handbook was developed for use at many levels in the electric and communication industries, including those involved in system design, construction, maintenance, inspection, standards development and worker training. The Handbook also discusses how the NESC Committee has developed the rules in the Code and responded to change proposals during the past 100 years. This allows users to understand how questions they may have dealt with in the past.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2019</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>China</keyword>
  <keyword>Electrical safety</keyword>
  <keyword>Electricity supply industry</keyword>
  <keyword>High-voltage techniques</keyword>
  <keyword>Communication systems</keyword>
  <keyword>Power transmission lines</keyword>
  <keyword>Mandarin</keyword>
  <keyword>Chinese</keyword>
  <keyword>communications industry safety; construction of communication lines; construction of electric supply lines; electrical safety; electric supply stations; electric utility stations; high-voltage safety; operation of communications sys­tems; operation of electric supply systems; power station equipment; power station safety; public utility safety; safety work rules; underground communication line safety; underground electric line safety.</keyword>
</bibdata>