<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Health informatics</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">Personal health device communication</title>
  <title type="title-part" format="text/plain">Device specialization -- Basic Electrocardiograph(ECG) (1 to 3-lead ECG)</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Health informatics - Personal health device communication - Device specialization -- Basic Electrocardiograph(ECG) (1 to 3-lead ECG)</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5871260</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE P11073-10406/D08, May 2011</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-6579-0</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>P11073-10406/D08, May 2011</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2011</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2011-06-06</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>Piscataway</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Within the context of the ISO/IEEE 11073 family of standards for device communication, this standard establishes a normative definition of the communication between personal basic electrocardiograph (ECG) devices and managers (e.g. cell phones, personal computers, personal health appliances, set top boxes) in a manner that enables plug-and-play interoperability. It leverages appropriate portions of existing standards including ISO/IEEE 11073 terminology and IEEE Std 11073-20601 information models. It specifies the use of specific term codes, formats, and behaviors in telehealth environments restricting optionality in base frameworks in favor of interoperability. This standard defines a common core of communication functionality for personal telehealth basic ECG (1 to 3-lead ECG) devices. Monitoring ECG devices are distinguished from diagnostic ECG equipment with respect to: including support for wearable ECG devices; limiting the number of leads supported by the equipment to three; not requiring the capability of annotating or analyzing the detected electrical activity to determine known cardiac phenomena. This standard is consistent with the base framework and allows multi-function implementations by following multiple device specializations (e.g., ECG and respiration rate).</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2011</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Informatics</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomedical informatics</keyword>
  <keyword>Medical information systems</keyword>
  <keyword>Basic ECG (1 to 3-lead ECG)</keyword>
  <keyword>medical device communication</keyword>
  <keyword>personal health devices</keyword>
</bibdata>