<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain">ISO/IEC/IEEE Draft Standard for Health informatics</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">Personal health device communication -Part 10420 Device specialization</title>
  <title type="title-part" format="text/plain">Body composition analyzer</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">ISO/IEC/IEEE Draft Standard for Health informatics - Personal health device communication -Part 10420 Device specialization - Body composition analyzer</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5407660</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Unapproved Draft Std P11073-10420_D7, Jan 2010</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-2863-7</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>P11073-10420_D7, Jan 2010</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2010</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Within the context of the ISO/IEEE 11073 family of standards for device communication, this standard establishes a normative definition of the communication between personal body composition analyzing devices and managers (e.g. cell phones, personal computers, personal health appliances, set top boxes) in a manner that enables plug-and-play interoperability. It leverages appropriate portions of existing standards including ISO/IEEE 11073 terminology and IEEE Std 11073-20601 information models. It specifies the use of specific term codes, formats, and behaviors in telehealth environments restricting optionality in base frameworks in favor of interoperability. This standard defines a common core of communication functionality for personal telehealth body composition analyzer devices. In this context, body composition analyzer devices are being used broadly to cover body composition analyzer devices that measure body impedances, and compute the various body components including body fat from the impedance.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2010</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Bioinformatics</keyword>
  <keyword>Medical services</keyword>
  <keyword>medical device communication</keyword>
  <keyword>personal health devices</keyword>
  <keyword>body composition analyzer</keyword>
</bibdata>