<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Utility Industry Metering Communication Protocol Application Layer (End Device Data Tables)</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Utility Industry Metering Communication Protocol Application Layer (End Device Data Tables)</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5606229</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE P1377/D8, October 2010</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-6507-3</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>P1377</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2010-10-19</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2010-10-19</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>Piscataway</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard provides common structures for encoding data in communication between End Devices (meters, home appliances, IEEE 1703 Nodes) and Utility enterprise collection and control systems using binary codes and XML content. The standard addresses the AMI and SmartGrid requirements as identified by the Office of Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability of the U.S. Department of Energy; the Smart Metering Initiative of the Ontario Ministry of Energy (Canada) and of Measurement Canada. The standard exposes sets of tables that are grouped together into sections that pertain to a particular feature-set and related function such as Time-of-use, Load Profile, Security, Power Quality and more. Each standard Table Set (Data Model) can be expanded or restricted by the Manufacturer of the IEEE 1377 Device or home appliance using XML/TDL descriptive registered syntax (XML-based Table Definition Language) and enterprise data-value management using EDL (Exchange Data Language) in a manner that is machine readable. Published jointly with NEMA and Measurement Canada, this standard provides Tables in support of Gas, Water and Electric sensors and related appliances. It also provides Tables for network configuration and management by referencing its companion standard IEEE 1703. IEEE 1377 is co-published as ANSI C12.19 and MC12.19.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2010</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Automatic meter reading</keyword>
  <keyword>Electricity supply industry</keyword>
  <keyword>Load flow control</keyword>
  <keyword>Power system management</keyword>
  <keyword>Home appliances</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE 1377</keyword>
  <keyword>ANSI C12.19</keyword>
  <keyword>End Device</keyword>
  <keyword>Utility Tables</keyword>
</bibdata>