<reference anchor="IEEE.P1589/D3, Oct 2019" target="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8890049">
  <front>
    <title>IEEE Draft Standard for an Augmented Reality Learning Experience Model</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IEEE">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>New York</city>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2019" month="November" day="1"/>
    <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
    <keyword>Augmented reality</keyword>
    <keyword>Machine learning</keyword>
    <keyword>Training data</keyword>
    <keyword>Immersive learning</keyword>
    <keyword>Virtual reality</keyword>
    <keyword>Augmented Reality</keyword>
    <keyword>E-Learning</keyword>
    <keyword>Workplace Training</keyword>
    <keyword>Learning Activity</keyword>
    <keyword>Learning Experience</keyword>
    <keyword>Performance Support</keyword>
    <keyword>Immersive Learning Environment</keyword>
    <keyword>Mixed Reality</keyword>
    <abstract>Augmented Reality (AR) promises to provide significant boosts in operational efficiency by making information available to employees needing task support in context in real time. To support according implementations of AR training systems,this document proposes an overarching integrated conceptual model that describes interactions between the physical world, the user, and digital information, the context for AR-assisted learning and other parameters of the environment. It defines two data models and their binding to XML and JSON for representing learning activities (also known as employee tasks and procedures) and the learning environment in which these tasks are performed (also known as the workplace). The interoperability specification and standard is presented in support of an open market where interchangeable component products provide alternatives to monolithic Augmented Reality-assisted learning systems. Moreover, it facilitates the creation of experience repositories and online marketplaces for Augmented Reality-enabled learning content. Specific attention was given to reuse and repurposing of existing learning content and catering to ‘mixed’ experiences combining real world learner guidance with the consumption (or production) of traditional contents such as instructional video material or learning apps and widgets.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>