<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Guide to Select Terminations for Shielded Power Cable 5</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">46 kV</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Guide to Select Terminations for Shielded Power Cable 5 - 46 kV</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4519421</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Unapproved Draft Std P1637/D10.2, Apr 2008</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-2511-7</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>P1637/D10.2, Apr 2008</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2008</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">The guide has been developed to provide a step-by-step process for selecting an appropriate termination that is commensurate with a particular underground cable design. Over the years, underground cables have been developed that employ many different insulating materials and many different shielding systems, such that, there are numerous issues to consider when selecting a termination for a particular cable design. Over the same period of time, many different termination methods and designs have been developed that serve the same purpose, but employ different application methodologies. The guide does not attempt to cover every cable and termination design, and is generally restricted to single conductor Underground Residential Distribution (URD) and power cable that have a voltage rating from 5 to 46 kV. By nature, the terminations referred to in this guide are considered to be “live front”, in that the terminations comprise a transition from an underground cable to an energized component or bus that is either bare or simply covered.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2008</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
</bibdata>