<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Environmental Assessment of Personal Computer Products, Including Notebook Personal Computers, Desktop Personal Computers, and Personal Computer Displays</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Environmental Assessment of Personal Computer Products, Including Notebook Personal Computers, Desktop Personal Computers, and Personal Computer Displays</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4810948</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Unapproved Draft Std P1680.1/D2, Feb 2009</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-4024-0</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>P1680.1/D2, Feb 2009</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2009</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">IEEE Std. 1680.1 provides a clear and consistent set of performance criteria for the design of personal computer products including notebook computers, desktop computers, and computer displays thereby providing an opportunity to secure market recognition for efforts to reduce the environmental impact of electronic products. This standard is intended to provide a tool for government, institutional and corporate purchasers. Product manufacturers may also use this tool to earn recognition in the consumer market, recognizing that certain criteria may not be applicable to all types of purchasers. There are three levels of conformance with this Standard. To achieve the first level, the product shall conform to all of the 23 required environmental criteria. To achieve the second level, the product shall conform to all of the required criteria plus at least 50% of the 28 optional criteria, and to achieve the third level the product shall conform to all the required criteria and at least 75% of the optional criteria. This Standard shall be updated and revised on a periodic basis to continue to set a higher performance standard for leadership products.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2009</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>computer</keyword>
  <keyword>computer display</keyword>
  <keyword>electronic product</keyword>
  <keyword>electronic product design</keyword>
  <keyword>environment</keyword>
  <keyword>environmental leadership</keyword>
  <keyword>environmental performance</keyword>
  <keyword>notebook computer</keyword>
  <keyword>personal computer</keyword>
</bibdata>