<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Wearable Cuffless Blood Pressure Measuring Devices</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Wearable Cuffless Blood Pressure Measuring Devices</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6745996</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE P1708/D03, February 2014</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-8955-0</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>P1708/D03, Feb 2014</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2014-01-01</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2014-02-20</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2014</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Within the context of the IEEE P1708 standard, it establishes a normative definition of wearable cuffless blood pressure measuring devices and the objective evaluation of this kind of devices. The standard is independent of the form of the device or the vehicle the device is attached to or embedded in. The standard is applicable to all types of wearable BP measurement devices that have different modes of operation (e.g. to measure short-term, long-term, snapshot, continuous, beat(s)-to-beat(s) BP or BP variability). This standard is, however, limited to evaluation of devices that does not use a cuff during measurement and does not cover evaluation of all sphygmomanometers that are used with an occluding or inflatable cuff for the indirect determination of BP on the upper arm or wrist. This standard provides guidelines for manufacturers to qualify and validate their products, potential purchasers or users to evaluate and select prospective products, and health care professionals to understand the manufacturing practices on wearable BP devices.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2014</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomedical equipment</keyword>
  <keyword>Medical devices</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomedical measurements</keyword>
  <keyword>Blood pressure</keyword>
  <keyword>Wearable computers</keyword>
  <keyword>Blood Pressure Measuring Devices</keyword>
  <keyword>Wearable</keyword>
  <keyword>Cuffless</keyword>
  <keyword>Evaluation</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
</bibdata>