<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Secure SCADA Communications Protocol (SSCP)</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Secure SCADA Communications Protocol (SSCP)</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8792418</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE P1711.2/D3 August 2019</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-6059-0</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>P1711.2/D3 Aug 2019</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2019-08-07</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2019-08-08</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2019-11-07</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">A cryptographic protocol to provide integrity with optional confidentiality for cyber security of substation serial links is defined in this standard. It does not address specific applications or hardware implementations and is independent of the underlying communications protocol.The elevated concern of cyber security throughout the power industry has created a need to protect communications to and from substations. This standard defines a cryptographic protocol known as Secure SCADA Communications Protocol (SSCP) that protects the integrity and, optionally, the confidentiality of asynchronous serial communications typically used by control system equipment. SSCP is primarily intended to protect serial SCADA communications, but can be applied to other serial communications, such as the maintenance ports of intelligent electronic devices. SSCP is independent of the underlying communications link and protocol (e.g., Modbus, DNP3, IEC 60870- 5), and is appropriate for serial communications over leased lines, dial-up lines, multi-drop links, radio, power line carrier, fiber optic, etc. SSCP is suitable for implementation in new equipment or for deployment in bump-in-the-wire devices retrofitting protection to existing systems.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2019</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>SCADA systems</keyword>
  <keyword>Protocols</keyword>
  <keyword>Network security</keyword>
  <keyword>Cryptography</keyword>
  <keyword>communications protocol</keyword>
  <keyword>confidentiality</keyword>
  <keyword>cryptography</keyword>
  <keyword>data acquisitions</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE 1711.2</keyword>
  <keyword>integrity</keyword>
  <keyword>SCADA</keyword>
  <keyword>secure communications</keyword>
  <keyword>SSCP</keyword>
  <keyword>supervisory control</keyword>
</bibdata>