<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Guide for Evaluating and Testing the Electrical Performance of Energy Saving Devices</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Guide for Evaluating and Testing the Electrical Performance of Energy Saving Devices</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8307804</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE P1889/D7.2, February 2018</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-4729-4</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>P1889/D7.2, Feb 2018</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2018-02-27</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2018-03-07</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2018-12-05</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Described in this guide are methods to evaluate and test the electrical performance of energy saving devices (ESDs). Measurement methods that focus on monitoring the power consumed or generated by the observed load or generator without the ESD connected into the circuit and with the ESD connected and energized into the circuit are described. Detailed protocols describe step-by-step the testing circuits, the type and accuracy of evaluation instrumentation, and the order of the test measurements. Special emphasis is given to sources of measurement errors due to incorrect connection of instrumentation, inadequate instrumentation, or incorrect interpretation of results. Contained in Annex B are practical examples and explanations of the physical mechanisms of phenomena that may cause errors. This guide applies to any electrically connected ESD controlling electrical power delivered from a source and powering an electrical load. While an independent, certified testing laboratory might be contracted to perform ESD testing, the intent of this standard is to provide guidance to those involved with ESDs wishing to obtain accurate and objective data to aid in evaluating ESD performance.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2018</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Performance evaluation</keyword>
  <keyword>Electrical equipment industry</keyword>
  <keyword>Energy efficiency</keyword>
  <keyword>Energy management</keyword>
  <keyword>electrical energy consumption</keyword>
  <keyword>electrical test protocol</keyword>
  <keyword>energy saving device</keyword>
  <keyword>ESD</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE 1889(TM) RESD</keyword>
  <keyword>retrofit energy saving device</keyword>
</bibdata>