<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard Method for Measuring the Shielding Effectiveness of Enclosures and Boxes Having All Dimensions between 0.1 m and 2 m</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard Method for Measuring the Shielding Effectiveness of Enclosures and Boxes Having All Dimensions between 0.1 m and 2 m</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6556932</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE P299.1/D6, July 2013</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-0-7381-8522-4</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>P299.1/D6, July 2013</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2013</on>
  </date>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2013-07-10</on>
  </date>
  <date type="issued">
    <on>2013-07-10</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city>Piscataway</city>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard provides uniform measurement procedures for determining the shielding effectiveness of electromagnetic (EM) shielding for a variety of enclosures and boxes having all dimensions between 0.1 and 2 meters in the radio frequency range not addressed by IEEE 299. This standard is divided into two parts: Part I - physically small, but electrically large enclosures and Part II - 0.75 to 2 meters. In addition to a number of annexes aiding the measurement of shielding effectiveness of these enclosures, Annex J addresses physically small and electrically small enclosures, and Annex K addressed electrically small enclosures in reverberation chambers. Problems occurring in the testing of small enclosures, having linear dimension less than 2 meters, are very different from determining the shielding effectiveness of large rooms and broad depending of the actual size of the enclosure itself. A number of other annexes are included that address rationale, mathematical formulas, selection of measurement techniques, preliminary measurement and repairs, wall-mounted monopoles, impedance mismatch correction, and using isolated monopoles in outer reverberation chambers.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2013</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>IEEE standards</keyword>
  <keyword>Electromagnetic shielding</keyword>
  <keyword>Magnetic shielding</keyword>
  <keyword>Reverberation chambers</keyword>
  <keyword>Shielded enclosures</keyword>
  <keyword>Electromagnetic shielding</keyword>
  <keyword>IEEE 299.1</keyword>
  <keyword>shielding effectiveness</keyword>
  <keyword>shielded enclosure</keyword>
  <keyword>reverberation chamber</keyword>
  <keyword>physically small</keyword>
  <keyword>physically large</keyword>
  <keyword>electrically small</keyword>
  <keyword>electrically large</keyword>
</bibdata>