<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Information Technology--Telecommunications and Information Exchange Between Systems--Local and Metropolitan Area Networks--Specific Requirements Part 3: Carrier Sense Multiple Access With Collision Detection (CSMA/CD) Access Method and Physical Layer Specifications (Revision of IEEE Std 802.3-2005 Including All Approved Amendments) Section 1</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard for Information Technology--Telecommunications and Information Exchange Between Systems--Local and Metropolitan Area Networks--Specific Requirements Part 3: Carrier Sense Multiple Access With Collision Detection (CSMA/CD) Access Method and Physical Layer Specifications (Revision of IEEE Std 802.3-2005 Including All Approved Amendments) Section 1</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4468789</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Unapproved Draft Std P802.3/D2.1, Feb 2008</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-3349-5</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>P802.3/D2.1, Feb 2008</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2008</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Ethernet local area network operation is specified for selected speeds of operation from 1 Mb/s to 10 Gb/s using a common media access control (MAC) specification and management information base (MIB). The Carrier Sense Multiple Access with Collision Detection (CSMA/CD) MAC protocol specifies shared medium (half duplex) operation, as well as full duplex operation. Speed specific Media Independent Interfaces (MIIs) allow use of selected Physical Layer devices (PHY) for operation over coxial, twisted pair or fiber optic cables. System considerations for multisegment shared access networks describe the use of Repeaters which are defined for operational speeds up to 1000 Mb/s. Local Area Network (LAN) operation is supported at all speeds. Other specified capabilities include: various PHY types for access networks, PHYs suitable for metropolitan area network applications, and the provision of power over selected twisted pair PHY types.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2008</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
</bibdata>