<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard Specifications for High Voltage (&amp;gt;1000 volts) Expulsion Type Distribution Class Fuses, Fuse and Disconnecting Cutouts, Fuse Disconnecting Switches, and Fuse Links and Accessories used with these Devices</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard Specifications for High Voltage (&amp;gt;1000 volts) Expulsion Type Distribution Class Fuses, Fuse and Disconnecting Cutouts, Fuse Disconnecting Switches, and Fuse Links and Accessories used with these Devices</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4811178</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Unapproved Draft Std PC37.42/D10, Mar 2009</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-3464-5</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>PC37.42/D10, Mar 2009</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2009</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Specifications for high voltage (above 1000 volts) expulsion type distribution class fuses, fuse cutouts, fuse disconnecting switches, their associated fuse links, disconnecting cutouts, and accessories for these devices are covered. All of these devices are intended for useon alternating current distribution systems. These include open and enclosed types of fuses and fuse cutouts and fuse disconnecting switches, as well as the fuse links of the type used exclusively with these devices; also open-link types of fuses, cutouts and their associated fuse links, open and enclosed types of disconnecting cutouts, fuse supports, fuse mountings and fusehooks of the type used exclusively with distribution class fuses, fuse cutouts, fuse disconnecting switches and disconnecting cutouts, fuseholders and removable switch blades of the type used exclusively with distribution class fuse supports and mounting brackets used for distribution class equipment and other accessories.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2009</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>expulsion fuses</keyword>
  <keyword>distribution class fuses</keyword>
  <keyword>high-voltage fuses</keyword>
  <keyword>fuse</keyword>
  <keyword>fuse applications</keyword>
  <keyword>fuse disconnecting switches</keyword>
  <keyword>distribution fuse cutouts</keyword>
  <keyword>fuse links</keyword>
</bibdata>