<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard Requirements for Liquid-Immersed Power Transformers</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">IEEE Draft Standard Requirements for Liquid-Immersed Power Transformers</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5089356</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Unapproved Draft Std PC57.12.10/D4.3, Jun 2009</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-3489-8</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>PC57.12.10/D4.3, Jun 2009</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2009</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This voluntary consensus standard sets forth the requirements for outdoor power transformer application. This standard is intended for use as a basis for performance, interchangeability, and safety of equipment covered, and to assist in the proper selection of such equipment. This is a product standard which covers certain electrical, dimensional, and mechanical characteristics of 50 and 60 Hz, liquid immersed power and auto-transformers. Such power transformers may be remotely or integrally associated with either primary switchgear or substations, or both, for step-down or step-up purposes base rated as follows: 833 KVA and above single-phase, 750 KVA and above three-Phase. This standard applies to all liquid-immersed power and auto transformers that do not belong to the following types of apparatus: Instrument Transformers, Step voltage and induction voltage regulators, Arc-Furnace Transformers, Rectifier Transformers, Specialty Transformers, Grounding Transformers, Mobile Transformers, Mine Transformers</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2009</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>Power transformer</keyword>
  <keyword>auto-transformer</keyword>
  <keyword>single-phase</keyword>
  <keyword>three-phase</keyword>
  <keyword>load tap changer</keyword>
  <keyword>electrical characteristics</keyword>
  <keyword>mechanical characteristics</keyword>
  <keyword>dimensional characteristics</keyword>
</bibdata>