<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain">Draft Amercian National Standard for Testing Unlicensed Wireless Devices</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain">Draft Amercian National Standard for Testing Unlicensed Wireless Devices</title>
  <uri type="src">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/4816161</uri>
  <docidentifier type="IEEE">IEEE Unapproved Draft Std PC63.10/D8.6F, Apr 2009</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="ISBN">978-1-5044-3545-1</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>PC63.10/D8.6F, Apr 2009</docnumber>
  <date type="created">
    <on>2009</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
      <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
      <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <country>USA</country>
      </address>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard is intended to cover procedures for testing the compliance of a wide variety of unlicensed wireless devices (also called unlicensed intentional radiators) including but not limited to: remote control and security devices, frequency hopping and direct sequence spread spectrum devices, anti-pilferage devices, cordless telephones, wireless medical devices, Unlicensed National Information Infrastructure devices, intrusion detectors, unlicensed wireless devices operating on frequencies below 30 MHz, automatic vehicle identification systems, and other unlicensed wireless devices authorized by a radio regulatory authority. The test procedures for new technology wireless devices will be added to future editions of this standard as soon as practical after consensus is achieved for compliance testing methods of the new devices. However, this standard excludes test procedures for unlicensed wireless devices already covered in other published standards, e.g., Unlicensed Personal Communication Services (UPCS) devices.</abstract>
  <copyright>
    <from>2009</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</name>
        <abbreviation>IEEE</abbreviation>
        <uri>http://www.ieee.org</uri>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <keyword>test procedures</keyword>
  <keyword>intentional radiators</keyword>
  <keyword>unlicensed wireless devices</keyword>
</bibdata>